Paul: Yeah, hello everyone, good morning.
Paul: Please check the chats. The chats are… Opened or not?
Paul: And I hope the audio is fine. It's letting you guys.
Paul: Alright, fine.
Paul: Alright, so let's discuss the agenda that we'll be talking about.
Paul: So, this week, we'll be going through Heidi. In the last class also, I've discussed Heidi, so today we'll be looking into the implementations.
Paul: Okay, and exactly the thing that I have discussed, so that part with respect to the paper that we'll be talking today.
Paul: Then we will move towards, hybrid search.
Paul: And then, finally, re-ranking. Next week, because I am planning to start Project 2,
Paul: And there you have text-to-SQL, okay? So, for that, I think from next week, we'll be discussing about text-to-SQL implementations a little bit, and how exactly it works, and then finally, we will start the project too.
Paul: Alright, so… this will be the main agenda. So, like, this week, IDE, hybrid search, and relanking. These three will be the major focus. Next week, text to SQL, and then project to that will be started.
Paul: Alright, if you don't know about the project, please look into that.
Paul: curriculum.
Paul: That you have.
Paul: Alright, so the first part, let's start…
Paul: I think I need to share today's repo.
Paul: I have today's report with me.
Paul: Okay, I'm sharing it in the chat, you guys can get it from the chat also.
Paul: Alright, so this is the report that will be talking today.
Paul: We'll be discussing. Everybody, so please take a clone and do the setup. Okay.
Paul: The same things that you do. I hope I don't need to repeat myself.
Paul: Yeah, please take 2 minutes, please do the setup, and then let me know.
Paul: Every once.
Paul: Again, I am sharing the link in the chat. If somebody has joined you, please take a clone of this one, and then please do the setup.
Paul: Creative virtual environments. I think a few packages are there.
Paul: The Lama Index part, in the last class, I've already shown you a few implementations, but this time, alright, few things.
Paul: Mainly the Langshan particip.
Paul: And once you guys are ready, please let me know.
Paul: Today's people.
Paul: Yes, I'll be adding it in motion later on. Right now, I have shared it directly. Get a clue.
Paul: I hope everybody has done the setup.
Paul: I'll be talking about that. The recap will be the abstract of the paper only, Montasar.
Paul: Setup ready, everyone.
Paul: It will take some time to reflect it.
Paul: Alright, fine, so… I think I can open…
Paul: Alright, so, in the last class, we have gone through the working of ID. Okay, so let's go through the abstract, it will be just like a recap.
Paul: So, in this particular paper, you can see December 2022, the paper comes from CMU and the University of Waterloo.
Paul: So, right here, right, Gao, so Liu Gao, he's, like, one of the main guys for this particular implementation. So, here, they are talking about, a little bit with respect to dense retrieval, okay? So, while dense retrieval has been shown effective.
Paul: And efficient across tasks and languages, it remains difficult to create effective, fully zero-shot, dense, distributable systems.
Paul: Now, this is the main problem that we do have, okay? Because during that particular point of time, like, how many of you know about zero-shot dense retrieval system? Okay, dense retrieval system, you know, but zero-shot.
Paul: So, what is the meaning of zero-shot? In the entire field of deep learning? What do you mean by that zero-shot word when you look at it?
Paul: Please let me know. Single prompt, yes. Not single prompt directly, I can say. Okay, without examples, I think, yes, no examples. Okay, whenever you are training, it means that there are no labels.
Paul: Don't think always from the perspective of examples. Okay, think from the labels. It means that you don't have any label data.
Paul: Okay, so if you think about labels as examples, it's fine. That is the mean ID. So technically, it means that
Paul: There is no concept of supervised learning.
Paul: Is this bacteria?
Paul: no supervised learning. It means that if you have your level data, that becomes your example, okay?
Paul: Alright, so right now, there are no level data for sure in our dense writable systems. So, when no relevance level is available, that is the core objective. So, in this paper, we recognize the difficulty of zero-shot learning and encoding relevance.
Paul: So, what is encoding?
Paul: Right here.
Paul: The context will be with respect to embedding, okay?
Paul: Instead, we propose to pivot through Heidi.
Paul: Given a query, Heidi first zero-shot the instructs, to an instruction following language model. Okay, so, like, instruction-based, models, where you can pass any type of model. So, generally, it can be Mistral, GPT models are also, I can say instruction-based.
Paul: Now, one of the examples they have given is InstructGPT. Okay, and really, the list of instruction-based models right now, most of them are. It's, of course, instruction-based, training as well as learning.
Paul: Okay, and here, in the last class also, I told you will be using an LLM, okay, to work with ID. So, similarly here, in this particular paper, they have given the talk with respect to InstructGPT to generate hypothetical embedding.
Paul: Okay? Now, the document captures relevance patterns, but is Unreal and me contain false details. Okay, so, the last class also I have told the hypothetical document that will be generated.
Paul: it will be having some type of relevance pattern. So, what do you mean by relevance patterns here?
Paul: I can say some amount of context with respect to the original documents that I have.
Paul: In my vector data analysis.
Paul: But there can be false amount of information also.
Paul: Then an unsupervised contrastive learning encoder. So, in the last class, I already told you about contriver, which will encode the document into an embedding vector.
Paul: This vector identifies the nevar root in a corpus embedding space where similar real documents are retrieved based on vector similarity. So, the core things, because right here, as we are talking with respect to dense retrieval, so for sure, the main, I will say, retrieval will take place based on vector similarity.
Paul: And majorly, like, cosine similarity here. This second step grounds the generated document to the actual corpus. Okay, now, because the hypothetical document that is getting generated is based on real documents.
Paul: Okay, so that's why they are talking about…
Paul: It's close to the ground truth.
Paul: With the encoder's bottleneck filtering out incorrect details. Okay, now that is the job of the main contributor here, okay, which you will be doing that filter operation.
Paul: Our experiment showed us Heidi significantly outperforms the state-of-the-art unsupervised
Paul: Intense Retriever, okay, which is referred to as the contraver here.
Paul: And show strong performance comparable to fine-tuned reviews across multiple tasks. And majorly right here, web search, Q&A, these three are the major ones, and a few multi-language also that they have tested.
Paul: Now, the cool thing is, you need an LLM, okay? So, and it should be instruction following language model, so IFLM that we do refer most of the times.
Paul: Now, this is the same thing in the last class I have told you. Now, this contraver. So, contraver models are also available in machine learning, where we teach how to identify similar, okay, or dissimilar documents that you have.
Paul: Now, based on this, we'll be, doing the implementation. So, here, the core thing is that LLM part. Now, it means that when I'll be asking the LLM, so how we'll ask the LLM? Through a prompt, yes or no.
Paul: It means that I will tell the LLM, you have to create a hypothetical document, and there will be some parameters. It can be based on some type of chunk, okay, and a few other things.
Paul: Now, it means that I'll be passing that information through a prompt.
Paul: And I'll be showing you that, because the custom implementation also I've kept, and with that, that I think I have the Lang Chen part. In the last class, if you remember.
Paul: I have already shown you the implementation with Llama Index. So, Llama Index part I will skip, but, Langshan. So, you can refer to the last example also.
Paul: Okay, alright, now…
Paul: Here, other things are mentioned here, okay? So, now, from your original documents, it will be generating the…
Paul: hypothetical document, and then finally, the contributor will come and look into your core part. So, blue color refers to the, real documents that you have. This one is basically that, LLM-based generated hypothetical modules.
Paul: And here, the main part is query. The entire thing happens with respect to the query. Once you pass the query, then only it will generate.
Paul: Now, I think…
Paul: few benchmarks that they have taken. So, right here, a few comparisons that they have done. So, NDGC is there, recall is there. So, BM25, I think everybody knows about BM25, the upgraded version of…
Paul: Tfiq. I think I have kept even one example of OCAPI BM25, okay? So, whenever we refer to BM25, actually, it's the OCAPI algorithm that we do have.
Paul: So, here, if I look into the metrics, really the metrics looks good if you directly try to, compare them with sparse-based and readings, or even through retrieve… contrever also.
Paul: And usually, it worked with respect to web search, so that's why in the first place, if you remember in the abstract part, they have told, okay, the result with respect to fine search and QA, it means question answering, or fact verification. In this part, it really worked. But really, in other part.
Paul: I feel that somehow it's toward the lower side, okay? So, always remember that it's not like that everywhere it votes.
Paul: Okay, so the downfalls are there. So that's why, very specifically, they have told that with respect to web search queue and effect, but again, on top of, mathematical, I can say data sets, sign facts, data sets, somehow I feel that in the maps one, it didn't perform really good.
Paul: Alright, now let's, start, looking into the implementation part, I think.
Paul: With respect to dataset part that they have not referred yet. So, this is a small paper, if you want, you can go through the entire part. So, they are… they'll be talking about a little bit about machine learning, controvers, those things.
Paul: So, first of all, I think the first notebook that you can open is this one, the Heidi one.
Paul: Alright, so let me just open mine one.
Paul: Aye.
Paul: Think with respect to the loss that you have.
Paul: PayPal link already, I have shared it.
Paul: Oak
Paul: Okay, people are joining late, again, asking for… Paper, paper.
Paul: Okay, PayPal link also, I've shared it in the chat. Okay, so I think you guys have done the setup, so let's start with the…
Paul: Implementation part.
Paul: So, first of all, little bit with respect to the theoretical part, the same thing that, we have kept it here.
Paul: If you really look into… okay, the things that I've discussed in the last class.
Paul: Okay, and generally, here I have taken a custom implementation, and then I'll be showing you, because the implementations, whenever you are working with respect to prompt, it can be different in every framework, so there is no fixed base solution.
Paul: Always remember that. Llama Index implementations can be different, similarly, LAN check, but the core objective remains the same, so probably 10-15% difference will be there.
Paul: Heidi health and the speed? No. Nothing with respect to the speed. It's an added operation. It means that it will take more time.
Paul: Similarly, hybrid search. It will take more time. Ranking, again, more time. These are more added operations, so for sure, these won't help you to speed up the retrieval process.
Paul: Alright, so, right here, I'll be doing my main operations with respect to GPT-4 right here. Okay, so first of all, you can do the installation, I think everybody has done that, so let me first of all check that everything is working fine or not.
Paul: Because this notebook, I have not executed.
Paul: In a few days, so let me check once.
Paul: In the last class, we have already gone through that. A, what is ID?
Paul: Please look into the last lecture, at least.
Paul: Today, we'll be doing the implementation.
Paul: In the last class, I have gone through the theoretical part.
Paul: Alright, so I think for everybody it should work, please check.
Paul: Because there are some helper functions also that I have kept it, but I think it should work. Please have a check on that.
Paul: Everybody, please check.
Paul: everything is getting imported, because here are some custom modules that I have kept it.
Paul: For everyone, please let me know.
Paul: Please let me know, guys, in the chat, only one. Una man told. What about others?
Paul: Alright, fine, so, I think for everybody it should work, there should not be any type of problems.
Paul: Now, here, if you look into, there are nothing major. I can say, poor things. Few things are there, in the helper functions, I have kept it, so if you want, generally, like, whenever you are working with…
Paul: So, I think here, these are few helpful functions that I do have. So, the core line chain imports, everything is available here only. So, if you look into the PDF loader, recursive character text bitter, OpenAI embeddings, these things are there.
Paul: And, I think, rank…
Paul: DoCAP implementation of BM25, that is also available.
Paul: And a few other things. I think majorly you guys should be familiar with these major imports that you have.
Paul: PDF is not available.
Paul: Alright, PDF might not be. Generally, I don't upload the data folder, that's why.
Paul: Mmm, just wait. I think probably in my case.
Paul: I will push that also, just give me one minute.
Paul: Data, data, data.
Paul: Because I have already commented the data part.
Paul: Mmm… alright, I have commented it only.
Paul: A spoon.
Paul: It should be uploaded.
Paul: Then do the installation of that Sonali.
Paul: Please don't tell me module not found errors at this time.
Paul: When you look into that, you should know that you might not have to.
Paul: It's not maybe. There is no possible.
Paul: It is already saved I know, because I've done the push, that's why.
Paul: Alright, just wait. Probably in Google Drive, I will upload all the files, and I will share it for now.
Paul: Major, we'll be working with the PDF only, so we can get that.
Paul: Alright, I have shared the link to the data. You can just create a data folder and keep the PDF there.
Paul: Yes, that's the PDF only.
Paul: I've shared the link also, so you guys can download the data and keep it inside the data folder.
Paul: Because… I think this…
Paul: For now, it's only the PDF, we don't need to worry about the other data files. That's only the PDF that you need.
Paul: I think everybody has access to the data file, I have shared it in the chat.
Paul: Alright, just create a data folder there, and place all the files, or only the PDF for now. The major requirement for today's class will be the PDF only.
Paul: Please let me know once you guys have done the setup.
Paul: The root folder only.
Paul: Let's check my structure, okay, in the root folder only created.
Paul: Imports loading, yes, it might take a time, because usually the imports are from the utils part.
Paul: Add below modules, okay, rank BM25, underscore, I think it will be.
Paul: Alright, fine. So, as you guys are telling, it's done, so let's proceed, right?
Paul: Now, let's focus on this, core part.
Paul: So, first of all, this is a custom, part that I have done it. Okay, so majorly, as you can see, a custom class that I have built.
Paul: right here, IDRetriever in it, and just focus on the arcs right now. The arcs are basically chunk size, which is 500.
Paul: And the chunk overlap 100 that I have passed. Now, these parameters are important because, in the prompt template, I will be passing them.
Paul: So, first of all, for generating the embeddings, okay, so what I will be using, I've taken here the OpenAI embeddings, just chunk size, the chunk overlap, and basically the vector store.
Paul: Okay, so for encoding the PDF, as you can see here, encode PDF,
Paul: That I have. Now, this module, if you directly refer here… Okay, so this is the… this is within the, I can say, helper function, because these functions I don't need to discuss with you. I feel everybody is familiar with these functions.
Paul: Yes, please check the code once. I don't think there should not… there should be any problem with anyone.
Paul: Please let me know.
Paul: Everyone, encode PDF? Okay, alright.
Paul: Alright, so always remember that if I miss something, okay, just focus on here, because this notebook doesn't need Chroma. Okay, so that's why I've not added that. Every package will have that specific requirement.
Paul: Alright, so,
Paul: Then codePDF.put… so these are the main things that I have initialized inside my constructor. Then defining my prompt, self.id prompt.
Paul: And right now, the input variables, two input variables that I have, the query and the chunk size. So generally, we don't talk about the chunk size, but chunk size is very important.
Paul: Now, given the question, now, whatever the question, or basically the query the user will be passing, based on that, generate a hypothetical document.
Paul: That directly answers the question. Okay, it means that based on the query that you were… the document should be detailed.
Paul: And in depth, the document size has to be exactly the chunk size characters.
Paul: Can you see here? The length of the document is defined based on which parameter.
Paul: Yes?
Paul: Based on which parameter, guys?
Paul: Remember, it's the chunk, so it means that you take the decision.
Paul: So don't think about the document as a big PDF document or something like that. Okay?
Paul: It is going to be based on the chunk.
Paul: Naya, please check. If you have an API limit error, please don't ask me. It means that there is some issue with your API only.
Paul: Alright, now, once you look here, very specifically, this is the core prompt that you have. And later on, you'll be passing it through a chain, as simple as that.
Paul: The implementation is very, very simple. Okay, so that's why I've just created a custom one here. So this is a core prompt that will be passing it to an instruction-based LLM. And right now, as we are working with, GPT-4 Mini does the job for us.
Paul: Now, in the next step, so generate the hypothetical document, input variables, as you can see, self, we are passing that, and we are invoking the chain, and finally, debretrieve. So, this is the part where generate, so I'm calling this function actually within this, okay, through the query that we have defined, and it will return the similar documents.
Paul: As simple as that. Now, this is the part where we are actually performing.
Paul: Vector similarities such.
Paul: I think this implementation is easy and pretty much clear.
Paul: The hypothetical document is getting generated just by passing the query.
Paul: Correct, just by passing the query, as well as your PDF document.
Paul: Here, I have this encode PDF mantage. Please look into the source code, guys.
Paul: I think the source code will be easy, because this is a complete scratch implementation that I am showing you right here.
Paul: How many… I think…
Paul: this part, there is nothing fancy here, it's pretty much simple Pythonic approach that I have taken.
Paul: The hypothetical document is based on LLM knowledge. No, it's not based on… it's based on the query.
Paul: And the document, the vector store document. And majorly, it, it is built on top of the query.
Paul: Okay.
Paul: Alright, so let me just, execute this one.
Paul: Alright, the class implementation that I have done. Now, I'll be creating an object of the instance.
Paul: Okay, and here, the core PDF path that I have passed.
Paul: Because, rest of the parameters, the default parameters are only the file part that I need to pass it here. So, based on that, I have created an instance, or basically the object of the class.
Paul: Now, let's talk here. So, here I'm asking a simple question, like, what is the main cause of the climate change?
Paul: Okay, and finally, like, this particular test query, I'll be passing it to this. So generally, if you look into, this is 5.7 seconds. Okay, so again, let me just execute this part.
Paul: Now, Abhishek is asking where we are getting the ID query from.
Paul: Abhisheed, from where we get query.
Paul: Can anybody get the query from Vector Store?
Paul: Here's how many of you think you get the query from VectorStore?
Paul: It is generated based on the query.
Paul: And then the vector store is correct, because the idea is you need to compare it with your real documents. That's where your main chunks within that vector store will be available.
Paul: I hope, I appreciate you get that.
Paul: Query doesn't come from vector store.
Paul: Please go through, because these are pretty much fundamentals.
Paul: So, right here, if you, really look into the results.
Paul: Okay, so, the results that you have, I have simply printed it, okay? And later on, these are basically the hypothetical documents that you have.
Paul: I'm showing you even the hypothetical document which is getting generated. So, generally, other places, so in my case, I have that particular option, so very simply, I'm showing you exactly what is the document.
Paul: Please, look into that, because later on for doc in results, so results part, this is simply… this is the output from the retriever, pretty much. But this is the core hypothetical document which has been generated.
Paul: I think for everybody, it should be working.
Paul: Yes, guys, please let me know.
Paul: Everybody can see the hypothetical document. Alright.
Paul: Now,
Paul: Coming to, Langchain ID implementation, because I have shown you custom implementation. Now, if you have this.
Paul: you already have this class. Can you plug… you can simply plug it, plug and play anywhere.
Paul: Now, coming to the Langchain implementation, so in Langchain, now this is… now, in the newer version of Langchain, it has been moved under the older version, so Langchain Classic has that particular chain of hypothetical document embedded. Now, this is the class that is available.
Paul: directly. It means that you don't need to pick up your implementation. If you want a line-chain-based implementation, simply you can use it.
Paul: Now, here what I have taken, so the loader, PyPTF loader, loading the documents in the first step.
Paul: Now, spreading, so here also I can use that in good PDF. Okay, it's pretty much, but few things with respect to retrieval that was not required, so that's why that particular definition that I have done quickly.
Paul: Now, here, creating the IP, your IDE embeddings, so again, the embedding selection, the LLM selection, and then directly I am calling my hypothetical embedder from LLM.
Paul: Okay? And, prompt key parts, so this is basically a web search.
Paul: template. So, whenever you look into PromptKey, there are multiple type of prompt templates that you have in Langchain. So, this is a pre-built template that comes from available that I will be using. So, generally, new websites is written, like, generator passage.
Paul: Based on the context that you have. Okay, now this is simply a template. Don't think it will perform a web search.
Paul: Okay? A simple prompt template.
Paul: This is just a template, guys.
Paul: How it can perform a web search.
Paul: There is no access, I'm not providing it any tool. This is a template.
Paul: If you don't know about this, because I think previously I've not discussed this one, so, let me talk about this one, actually.
Paul: There are other, templates also. You can see here, templates.langchen.com.
Paul: Multiple type of templates are available.
Paul: It means that every time writing the prompt is not that. So, from here, web search is the most common one, so that I have picked up. For majorly, for most of your tasks, you can get a template.
Paul: Alright, now… Here, web search template, you can directly search from here.
Paul: I think you will be getting that. Okay, the name is confusing because the core thing that… but it is the most simple for easiest form of generation that you have. You can create your own customs also.
Paul: I think web-based templates you will be having.
Paul: Direct web search is not there, but with respect to research, I am showing you. Can you see here? Tags, description, exactly what is that? If you want to use this particular template, what are the other package requirements?
Paul: For websites, you don't need any such package, so that's why it's much… becomes easier, rather than writing a custom template. So these are widely used ones, and really, like, it's not necessary every time. If you really look into, everybody has got this one, like, sign-in to update some easily 0, 0. Once you do a sign-up, then you can rate it also.
Paul: The name is confusing, but don't think that it's performing a web search. It's just a template.
Paul: All right.
Paul: Now, based on this… So, let me execute this one.
Paul: Okay, so I think here, the requirement of Chroma that you have, you can simply do a pep install Chroma.
Paul: Okay, ChromaDB, and there are two packages. So, for Chroma, what are the packages that you need, guys?
Paul: what are the packages? Because even if you look into, this is an older import. The new import uses Langchen underscore Chroma, just remembered that.
Paul: Okay, but the old import is working, so it's fine.
Paul: the core thing we can achieve. Now comes for the vector store part. Now, this is the part with respect to the retrieval. Can you see here, vector store? Okay, so from document, and then based on chance, the ID embeddings, and then finally I am passing.
Paul: I'll be passing my query in the next step, so activating this, and right here, invoking my
Paul: main chain, I can say.
Paul: So, from here, I'm getting some type of results. So, majorly looking into the roles of technology with respect to
Paul: Climate change mitigation.
Paul: Right now, Okay, so my chunk that is coming, like, protect ecosystem, this is fine.
Paul: Because right now, it's, pretty much the chunk, or I can say the top retrieval that is coming. And right now, I have just shown you the first one.
Paul: Okay.
Paul: Install ChromaDB.
Paul: Don't tell me module not found error, at least. I think everybody should be smart by this time that they can figure it out if somebody says no module named ChromaDB.
Paul: Alright.
Paul: Now, mantage context cannot be hypothetical.
Paul: How many of you think context can be hypothetical?
Paul: Fundamentals, stick to fundamentals.
Paul: context remains in your vector TV, so how it can be hypothetical.
Paul: Yes, correct. ID document is generated by the LLM knowledge only. Correct, exactly. Avishly.
Paul: Holy…
Paul: Is this part clear? The language and implementation that I have shown? I think for everybody it should work.
Paul: Okay, and then coming to the next step, now this is the other minimal usage through a chain part that I was actually improving on top of this one. So, this implementation also, you can… if you want to use, you can take this one.
Paul: Okay, now this is the other implementation. Just, I was trying to do some changes based on, like, chains you guys used. So, for that chain, but implementation, this is a much newer version, I can say.
Paul: Okay, so as compared, because here I'm not using Lanishen Classic, because I don't know, probably after one year if LanChain Classic was removed. For that part, I have just kept this one.
Paul: So, if you look into the implementation, please let me know.
Paul: How many of you are comfortable with this particular implementation?
Paul: Because I know we have gone through this implementation multiple times.
Paul: Please let me know.
Paul: Please let me know, guys, in the chat. Everybody is fine with this particular implementation.
Paul: Yes, take your time. 2 minutes, take your time.
Paul: Because I feel that everything that you have, we have gone through this.
Paul: Don't focus on the imports part, directly focus here. Loading the PDF, nothing new. Creating a vector store, nothing new. LLM initial variation, nothing new. Then, ID prompt, just write a passage answering based here on the question.
Paul: Okay, a simple prompt that I have used. Then comes your helper function. Okay, now this also, we have, and finally create the chain.
Paul: This will be the chain of the earlier process, yes. Now, here I am not using that direct class which is available, the hypothetical document template.
Paul: That's the main thing. Here, it's pretty much step-by-step that I have taken.
Paul: Alright, now this implementation, this is also fine if you want to work with. I feel this is much more the newer version, or the older part has been, like, has moved into Langston Classic, so I'm not sure in future whether the support will be there or not.
Paul: Okay, and so, just kept this part so that if you want to take this particular one.
Paul: I think, then another, implementation, or I've kept it.
Paul: Okay, now, see, the idea is that the same thing if I try to break it into multiple ways.
Paul: Because implementations, I feel that this particular implementation, if I'm actually building it, I might use it. Okay, so if you want to check this implementation, it does the same thing.
Paul: If you really look into, but this is the other rupee. And if you really look into the format takes, this is the retriever, what for everything I have a function through that, I'll be later calling it.
Paul: And finally, passing our chat prompt template, so using the following context that you have.
Paul: Now, here, a simple comparison with respect to a standard rag that I have included. Okay, and later on with an ID chain. So, two different chains are here. The standard chain and the high D chain. If you want to perform a comparison. Okay, so for that part, I have kept it.
Paul: Now, let me just, run this one.
Paul: I think it should work.
Paul: I've tested it last week, but I feel… yes, both the chains will come.
Paul: Now, if you look into the standard tracks, it will be somehow better.
Paul: Okay, so it means that whenever you are high… but remember, like, high D is at least much faster if you try to compare them with hybrid search or with re-ranking.
Paul: So Heidi is a process that I can always keep it. I feel that it's much…
Paul: safer, it means that the speed won't be very, very high. Whereas for re-ranking and for others, at least I know that
Paul: Probably 2 to 3 seconds might get added.
Paul: on top of your final, or top of the standard rat design. So at high D, at least better with respect to the speed.
Paul: Yes, correct. Show him that particular approach.
Paul: Please go through this and let me know, because there is nothing new in this particular chain. One is a standard chain, one is that ID chain, two different chains that I have.
Paul: Because these things with respect to Lansion, I have discussed this so many times, so I feel that…
Paul: You guys should be comfortable with LanChain by this time.
Paul: That's why I'm doing Lang Chen, then Lama Index, then again, Lang Chen. In that way, at least things will be here.
Paul: Now, A is asking, what is the benefit of hydrogen?
Paul: That is where I've done the implementation of IDE.
Paul: One is the standard chain, where there is no IT.
Paul: How many of you are able to understand this part? Please let me know. If you don't understand, then you're gonna have to repeat myself.
Paul: Because from the starting week, we started Lancin, and this is the same thing that I have discussed.
Paul: Do you want me to do a repeat part? Alright, fine.
Paul: You don't understand, really, like, if you don't understand this, then really… Nothing that I can do.
Paul: Alright. Now, dilution of context, we'll be talking about that. Let's focus. Now, this import part, how many of you are comfortable with this?
Paul: Yes. Now, in the next step, I am loading the PDF.
Paul: I'm creating the vector store, initializing my retriever, initializing my LLM. All the initializations that I have done here.
Paul: Then I have few helper functions. One is formatting the documents, this every time you have used.
Paul: Now for, concatenating the chunks, then you have your retrieve context.
Paul: Okay, now this is where you will be invoking your retriever, so I will be making a direct function call. And another, this is a direct one for standard… the standard chain that I'll be using, and this is retrieve with ID. Here, I am actually passing that hypothetical input that you will be getting, and that even I have printed it out.
Paul: Okay, now through this, I'll be basically, invoking. So, you can see retriever.inpoc, and I'm passing out that hypothetical.
Paul: Now here, in the return part, so the context with respect, and finally the questions that I have.
Paul: Now, this is the Q&A prompt, so that I have simply kept it, the standard rack, directed cable.
Paul: Those… this is a simple LCL chain that you have. LCL chain.
Paul: there is no… code is good, but trying to understand the purpose. I've just shown you the comparison. If you are adding RAG, if you are adding ID, if you are not adding ID, that's the only difference.
Paul: It's not necessary to do a comparison, but if you feel… the idea is always to do… you have to compare. Whenever you are working, and you are trying to build a rad, you have to always do that comparison. So the idea was to shoot a comparison. So, for that, I have kept two different chains. One was that standard chain, and the other one was that,
Paul: tag with Heidi.
Paul: If standard track gives a better result, why do we use ID?
Paul: Cms, it's not always that your standard rack will give you the result, you have to understand that.
Paul: Okay, so I don't feel that every time.
Paul: Yes, I can say the cost of your solution will increase, for sure, because the number of token generation, that will be a little bit toward the higher side, but again, it depends upon the chunk size, so that's why, generally, it's a good practice to pass that chunk size parameter. And 500 tokens, Abhishek, really, it's not a cost thing that we can take.
Paul: Now, Naga, why that you are asking, please let me know why.
Paul: For what part that you have.
Paul: Okay, so which party want to ask why? Please let me know. Like, LCL chain, why? Like, this is an LCL chain implementation, simply that I have done.
Paul: How many of you get this particular implementation? I feel that I have taught you this particular chain implementation.
Paul: More than 4 to 5 times.
Paul: Okay, now this is the simple rack chain that I have, and this is a simple ID chain.
Paul: Heidi will work better in generalized use cases, but also work in specific? Yes, it will work in specific also.
Paul: It's not like, at least I can say the part with respect to embedding generation, or in some cases, it doesn't work. But here, it really doesn't matter.
Paul: Now, if you look into the paper, so in this paper… so, first of all, always understand what is written in the paper.
Paul: In this paper, very specifically, they're talking about web search. How many of you feel that web search is a very dominel-specific task, and not much more towards generalized tasks? Q&A. Fact verification?
Paul: For these type of tasks, it works, so really, it works. So, the domain is not so much important.
Paul: Because based on what it will be, it means that if you ask a query, if that query becomes Roman-specific, so for sure, based on that only it will try to generate.
Paul: Now the question comes, if you have very domain-specific data, try to pick up a LLM which is domain-specific.
Paul: Rather than using ChatGPT.
Paul: Is this part clear?
Paul: It means that for your use case.
Paul: Because here, what you need to bring, you need to bring that LLM into the picture, an instruction, fine-tuned one. So, in that case, you need to pick up the correct LLM. So, why you will be using a chat GPT model or an anthropic model in that case?
Paul: I hope you are getting it.
Paul: If you have a domain-specific data, based on that, you have to bring that domain-specific. At least, it means that if you are working with respect to medical, there are medical LLMs that are available. You can use that. It's not necessary, you have to build your own fine-tuned solution.
Paul: But at least pick something from that particular domain.
Paul: Hyde is, again, plug-and-play module, I feel that anywhere it can be used.
Paul: As compared to others, really. Like, Heidi doesn't take so much time, so I feel that you should use Heidi always.
Paul: Because by generating that particular hypothetical document, I feel somehow it's an added advantage of 10-15% improvement that you can get. I cannot say the improvement can be very, very high, but 10-15% improvement is also good. MS.
Paul: Okay.
Paul: So, Subhaj is asking, when we're working, we want answers from the internal document, so we should not use high DE
Paul: Alright, fine. It's not necessary. In the paper only, it has told that it CAN generate false information.
Paul: So, in the paper also, it has been told, so it's not really a problem, you can take that.
Paul: KIDI is a part of query translation. Yes, you can, think, like, query translation is…
Paul: That term translation can be used in multiple ways. If you think in that way, Rahul, it's fine.
Paul: Translating can be with respect to other language transformations also, but if you really think with respect to that, so that particular space is also fine, I feel.
Paul: Is there a specific case? When we do it, we can use it in any use case, I feel. I feel that for any domain-specific, just be sure you are picking up a correct LLM. That's a poor thing.
Paul: Okay, sometimes even for Heidi, I have seen people using a totally different tail.
Paul: Yeah, okay, so some open source LLMs that they do use, which are very specifically trained on domains, specific data that you can use. You should have at least an open source license so you can do the implementation.
Paul: In every use case, try to add it. ID, like, I feel that you can plug and play ID every time.
Paul: Is this part clear for everyone? Please let me know.
Paul: Alright, now, two different ones. Then I have kept the implementation of Langshan, but I have already, the Llama Index also, but I have shown you in the last class, so you guys can do the implementation if you want. So really, I have not executed this part.
Paul: Alright, so I think, going forward, I will suggest everyone that use ID. ID is, like, it's a lightweight operation, and somehow it helps with respect to the retrieval by 10-15%.
Paul: That's the highest level data field.
Paul: You don't need to do multiple, iterations, Murta, because we know in the… see, when false information comes into the picture, you have to understand how much false.
Paul: I'm not telling in the… even in the mean paper also, it's written. So it's not… you don't have to do multiple generations of that.
Paul: Okay, now, for that, you have another, like, multi-query concept that comes into the picture, if you want to generate that. But here you don't need.
Paul: just generate a single hypothetical document. The idea is that at least that hypothetical document will have better 30% context. Probably 70% rest generated, core content of the document can be of false information. But that 30%, if it becomes 40%,
Paul: Just think, in your retrieval, added 223%. It becomes 50%. Again, in your retrieval, 2-3% added benefits.
Paul: Okay, so really, you cannot control that generation, because here, false information, for sure, it can be there. In some cases, you might feel that, yes, there is not a false information, but I feel that more than 50% of the times, there will be at least 30% false info. So, really, it won't
Paul: amper, because if 30% is there, I know 70% is… At least good.
Paul: So, there it will help.
Paul: So somehow, that… that's why you always take a 10% to 15% improvement on top of your original retrieval that you have. So, that's why I feel that this is… this operation is lightweight as compared to other operations that you have.
Paul: No, no, those are different things I'll be talking about. I've already shared the notebook, but that's different now.
Paul: Okay? Then in which task? Then in which task we can use in every task.
Paul: If you're working with RAG, you can always use ID.
Paul: Is this part clear for everyone?
Paul: There is no task-specific thing here.
Paul: Is this part clear for everyone? This is not a task-specific, this is a general component.
Paul: Which can be used by anyone.
Paul: How many of you are getting this? It's a generalized…
Paul: Okay. And if you have a domain-specific data, please pick up a domain-specific LLM. That's the main requirement.
Paul: It will be probably in millisecond.
Paul: Close to, I think, probably, like, 100 to 150 milliseconds.
Paul: Okay? Abhishek, you can calculate the latency. Just do a start and end time, okay, and try to compare the calculation. In this comparison, if you are trying to do… can you do the simple call start time and end time at that time, okay, and do your own.
Paul: the research. You will understand, it will be probably in, like, 100 to 150 milliseconds that I feel.
Paul: Alright, now, this part we have discussed. Now, the next thing, we'll be starting with respect to, I think our next notebook is with respect to fusion retrieval data, or basically hybrid search in simple terms that I will start.
Paul: Okay, so this part is done. I think I can save it for a later task, yes.
Paul: Alright, now a little bit with respect to theory that we'll be discussing.
Paul: So I think I need to get back to my notes.
Paul: Yes, it is free.
Paul: Alright, so in the last task, we have already gone through that part of Heidi.
Paul: Alright, sparse sentence vector also, we have gone.
Paul: Hmm… I'll get free.
Paul: So, if you remember in the last class, I think we have gone through, that part, okay, with respect to sparse part and few topics that I have told. If you have not gone through, just be sure you are going through that.
Paul: Now,
Paul: two vectors. Now, the idea is to bring two different types of vector search. One is your sparse vector search that you have.
Paul: Okay, so for those, also the algorithms that I have written. Okay, and finally, your dens. DENS, you guys have been doing it in this entire course.
Paul: So, let's start. So, hybrid search.
Paul: The idea is to combine your sparse vectors… And… delth vectors.
Paul: Okay? Now, the question comes how you will merge them, because…
Paul: getting a rank-based result from, I can say, a sparse vector, so this part is easy, as compared to dense vectors, this particular approach you guys have already taken.
Paul: So, the new thing can be sparse vectors. So, sparse vectors, I think you guys have done some type of implementation. If you remember TFIDF,
Paul: from SKLearn.
Paul: the simplest one that you can get started with, okay, at any point of time. So, right here, now, in this particular implementation, I'll be taking some sparse, dense, okay, and then finally I'll be performing a
Paul: merge operation. Now, this merge operation
Paul: this merge. It means that I need to combine. So, right now, it's not actual merging of two vectors, rather than… from here also, I'll be getting my…
Paul: Ranked results?
Paul: Okay, now the idea is to compare these two ranks, and finally get my new one.
Paul: Okay, so how to combine both the information? So, let's try to understand, first of all. Now, generally, this term is referred to as fusion, okay, because once we have discussed the initial implementation, I'll be talking about your…
Paul: Fusion Retrieval this time.
Paul: R, R, F.
Paul: Rank, Okay, reciprocal fusion.
Paul: This is the, main technique because of that, fusion retrieval, or sometimes hybrid retrieval also, we might see.
Paul: Okay, now this particular concept, I'll be taking an example, and I'll be showing you the calculation. But first of all, let's try to understand the computation of sparse vectors, delvectors, computation you guys already know, because we'll be making it through an API call.
Paul: So, right here, for our sparse vector generation, a few algorithms that I have told, but a few other algorithms.
Paul: After this particular fusion retrieval, I'll be looking into it. So, till now, what is the best algorithm for sparse vector that you guys know? Please let me know in the chat.
Paul: Because this is pure NLP, this is nothing related to RAG that I'm asking.
Paul: What is the best one?
Paul: bag of words, how can you say? Mitesh?
Paul: TFIDF, fine, I can say TF-IDF is fine.
Paul: One hot, that is the worst in the market.
Paul: count vectorizer to a certain level, what to wake, at least, yes. What to wake is where I feel that it's, better, what to wake, really, in real-world scenarios.
Paul: Inverted index, in some cases, only that works out.
Paul: Dmv25 is the upgraded version. Alright, fine, like, I'll be talking about an upgraded version, okay, on Transformers-based. Glove, really, right now, it's not so much important.
Paul: Alright, fine. Looks like none… none of you have gone through that particular concept. Today, I'll be talking about them. That's why I've kept that little bit about sparse, but…
Paul: Fine, so let's get back to the document, and let's try to look into the implementation.
Paul: So, first of all, okay, alright, let me just write, the formulas from one part, I think. That will be better.
Paul: I think I will be having that particular image just with Fusion Retrieval.
Paul: I need the image, let me get it.
Paul: I'm just looking for my image.
Paul: Alright, now, the question comes, so let's take an example. I will be using any algorithm. For now, let's take BM25.
Paul: Okay, so this BM25 I'll be using.
Paul: For generating my sparse vector.
Paul: Now, the question comes your dense vector generation.
Paul: There is no algorithm for that. Okay, for dense vector, I think everybody knows. I'll be making
Paul: call to the OpenAI.
Paul: Yes, like here, OpenAI.
Paul: For our dens… vector generation.
Paul: Now the question comes combining the score a little bit. Okay, so just focus on this part, this…
Paul: Because something with respect to formulas that I'll be talking about.
Paul: Now, the, how we will do the combination?
Paul: Okay? So, the first thing that comes, you have to take the weighted sum of normalized scores. So, whatever the score that you'll be getting.
Paul: Those will be the simulative scores only. Okay, so the weighted… some.
Paul: abnormalized. You can even look into the notebook, you will be getting. The same implementation that I'll be doing, which I'm writing in.
Paul: The first part is getting the weighted sum of the normalized scores.
Paul: And then, in the next step that we'll be taking, we'll be taking an alpha parameter. Okay, now, this is a hyperparameter for now, this alpha, you can play with this value, and then finally comes… this needs to be multiplied with your vector stored chunk, so I will write…
Paul: The vectors to the result that you have.
Paul: And plus 1 minus…
Paul: Alpha, I think it is 1 minus alpha, that needs to be multiplied with your BM25 scores.
Paul: Okay, now this is the core formula that you have. Even in the notebook, if you look into, we'll be having this particular formula. Through this formula, we'll be first
Paul: Combine the scores. Now, once we get the final scores, again, we have to perform a normalization operation. A mean-max normalization for BM25, very specifically, which is required.
Paul: Okay, mean max?
Paul: Normalization.
Paul: Yes, required for your BM25 schools.
Paul: Okay, and then finally, we will invert and normalize the vectors too, so an invert operation that we do.
Paul: And what are normalized?
Paul: So all these operations, I'll be showing you exactly in the notebook, also it is available. Okay?
Paul: Alright, now, when I'm writing, so these are vector scores, or dense vector. So this is for our sparse, and this is for our tens.
Paul: two things.
Paul: Okay, so at every point of time, whenever you are performing this normalization, so this normalization needs to be taken in both levels.
Paul: Now, let's try to look into the implementation, first of all, exactly what I have done, because here I have written the formula, it will be better if you look into the notebook directly. Things…
Paul: Will easier for you to understand.
Paul: So, right here, let's, look into the first part.
Paul: I think this has made this one.
Paul: Alright, now… Ugh.
Paul: Here, I've taken an input. Now, this is the core one, so if you really look into…
Paul: This comes… okay, so…
Paul: This is a package that you have, I think this is available directly in Lanschain also.
Paul: Okay, so this is the core one that I am using.
Paul: And even if you look into the Wikipedia of BM25, you will get that, the same implementation that you have.
Paul: Okay, Wikipedia BM25. Can you see? The original name comes Okapi, and it is used in information retrieval. Can you see in which year it was developed? Pretty old, I can say.
Paul: Okay, and this is the actual formula. So, I told you the upgraded version of TFIDM, so this is where, actually, you can look into.
Paul: Holy cow.
Paul: Now, just be sure you have this package in your system, okay, or otherwise, please do the installation, and directly, like, through Langchain Community Retrievers, like BM25 Retriever is available, that you can take the implementation.
Paul: Now, what I will do, so let's get back here to the notebook. I will just, first of all, try to load my inputs.
Paul: Now, the same PDF, but I'll be using the climate change PDF for now.
Paul: dimension of the vector needs to be handled through RRF, Mantaj, I will come to that particular point. So there, really, that dimension doesn't matter.
Paul: Alright, now, I think, this is the function that I have to load the PDF, so pretty much common ones, I can say.
Paul: So, encode PDF and spread documents. Two simple parameters. This is…
Paul: Even you have this implementation in your helper functions. So, from here, two things that I'll be getting, my vector store and the clean text. Clean text refers to the chance.
Paul: Okay, and then comes the vector store initialization that I have done here, which is the files vector store.
Paul: Now, here I have taken a simple example just to show you that BM25
Paul: Okay, now this is nothing related to LanChain, nothing. It's pure, classic BM25 implementation. Directly from the package, rank underscore BM25 that I have taken.
Paul: Now, in this particular example, so, first of all, I have imported it. I have just taken a few sample documents.
Paul: Then, on top of that corpus, a simple split is required, because the idea is two… three separate documents that are required, so a simple tokenized corpus that I am taking into account.
Paul: Now, this tokenized corpus, if you want, you can print it out also, so if I…
Paul: Print it out exactly how your corpus looks like.
Paul: Let me show.
Paul: So, in this algorithm, in any type of classical NLP algorithms, what is the most important thing?
Paul: Vocabulary, Yes or no? Vocabulary, according to classical NLP rules that we have.
Paul: Obviously, this telling elasticity style also is this concept, yes.
Paul: In Elasticsearch, they use, but they train their own, models, actually. Okay, few things are different with respect to Elastic, okay? But right now, we won't be talking about that. Just focus on this particular implementation. I'm just showing you that BM25 part.
Paul: Okay, so now, finally, on top of this, I'm passing the tokenizer here.
Paul: what is the exact thing that I have? So, you might say that, yes, it's not correctly tokenized. How many of you feel that this is not correctly tokenized?
Paul: Even I know it's not correctly tokenized, because question mark, exclamation mark, this should have been different. I can take a better implementation for spaCy, but that is not the goal here. The idea was to show a version of the tokenized corpus to you.
Paul: Now here, so… now the question comes, okay, let me pass a query, like, windy and London. Okay, now this tokenized query, again, I'll be splitting them.
Paul: Now, on top of this, VM25 gets post, which is basically the tokenized query that I am passing, and then let's print it out.
Paul: Okay, now this is what actually your score looks like.
Paul: Okay, so simply you can see, now this is what?
Paul: This is what type of embedding, Gaesh?
Paul: This is what type of embedding.
Paul: This is pure BM25 construct, nothing related to that. This is a sparse.
Paul: Okay, and generally, in the real world, the size of the vocabulary will be very, very, very big. Because of that, you will be having a lot of zeros.
Paul: Okay, so right now, a simple two zeros that directly you can see.
Paul: Okay, so right now, this is my, actual, I can just pass embedding. And then finally, get top end through which you can access the core document, so it is quite windy in London. So, this is the actual document that I, got.
Paul: Okay, so just keep this implementation for your reference. If somebody is totally unfamiliar with BM25, it's easier for them to understand.
Paul: Sparse is always the key value kind of structure, Noah, Vijit.
Paul: How there is a key value?
Paul: Everything, for example, if I take a vector of 300 dimension, there is no some key value concept there. It's purely a lot of zeros, and then finally you have some numbers.
Paul: Alright, now, here, create BM25 index that I am creating. This is not a dense vector index, so input to this particular function will be a list of documents, and the output format will be based on VM25O copy.
Paul: So, it will create a VM index, so tokenized docs, doc.split, on top of your original, and it will finally return the document.
Paul: I think this is the core function for our sparse embedding generation. Is this part clear for everyone?
Paul: I will come to that.
Paul: Okay, now here I'm passing directly the clean text, which is basically the chunks.
Paul: Generally, you pass it to a dense vector, like, you will be passing it to an LLM, okay, which will help you to generate, but here I'm passing my cleantext, or basically the chunks, here, to this particular function. So based on that, my sparse vectors, that will be generated.
Paul: Okay, so let me just run this particular function and pass this.
Paul: Okay, now this is the core function that I was talking about.
Paul: Now, the thing that I have written it in the notes, let's try to understand everything I have written it here in the form.
Paul: Okay, so here, in the fusion retrieval, so the vector store.
Paul: the BM25, the query K, the top K, and the alpha parameter.
Paul: Okay, now the alpha parameter is a hyperparameter.
Paul: Simply.
Paul: Now, here I have taken a 0.5, okay, and it will return, basically, a list of documents.
Paul: Now, this… first of all, I have taken an epsilon. So, generally, in most of the cases, why we take epsilon? A very small number.
Paul: In the entire field of deep learning, why we take an epsilon?
Paul: What is the purpose?
Paul: Overfitting reduced group, totally out of the context, there is nothing related to overfitting.
Paul: to avoid getting zero value. Aniral is correct.
Paul: John, we learning rate, not… you're… in deep learning, nobody is at such a learning rate point.
Paul: Triple Z, like, how many times here? 8, like, 001. The main purpose one, that your denominator doesn't become zero. Okay, that is the main purpose of entire deep learning. Guys, these are fundamentals.
Paul: Please keep on fundamentals, but… Okay, now…
Paul: here, if you really look into this, through this, I will always maintain that my denominator value. So these things, if anybody has gone through the concepts of.
Paul: The first concept, that comes here, that one. What do you say?
Paul: your optimizers, majorly in most of the optimizers. If you have learned about RMS prop, if you have learned about Atom, everywhere this epsilon comes, even in your ad account.
Paul: Yeah, how many… I don't know if you know about that, even in NADAM it comes. Okay, so pretty much fundamental deep learning.
Paul: Now, in the next step, you have your vectors2.similaritySearch. Okay, now this is your, first of all, initialization that you were doing here. And right here, can you see this is blank? Okay, so later on, I will be passing something, so pretty much a placeholder for now.
Paul: Then, in the next step, I am performing a BM25 search.
Paul: So, through GetSchools. If you remember last time also I showed you, if you are getting through this, so GetSchools, you'll be getting the schools here right now.
Paul: Now, in the next step… This is the place…
Paul: Where you are performing your dense search. So, see, VM25 search, this is a vector search. And can you see here, I need scores, because this will throw me scores, and this will. So, that's why it's not the pure similarity search directly. Here, I'm returning width score.
Paul: Yes?
Paul: Tell me, guys, how many of you got these 4 lines.
Paul: the implementation that I have done.
Paul: Others, let me know in the chat. Only 2 or 3 people are telling us. These are custom implementations, otherwise…
Paul: Direct implementations are also there.
Paul: Okay, alright, this part clear. Now, I told you, like, normalization of this course, so for that, I have taken into account this particular… here I have used NumPy, it's not necessary every time you use NumPy only.
Paul: Okay, but the simpler version through NumPy later on, if you're working with…
Paul: I can say, operation based on GPU, then you can switch it to torch based on other operations also.
Paul: Puvandiram is telling, can you repeat one more time?
Paul: Alright, now, this is the absolute definition that I have done, which will make sure that my denominator doesn't become zero. Now, first of all, we are fetching all the documents, then we are getting the BM25 search for that, whatever will be my sparse.
Paul: Vector scores, I'm getting that through this particular implementation, and from here, I'm getting my dense vector search scores.
Paul: Okay, so here, this part, we are just getting the schools. Now, in the next lesson, first of all, here I am performing… what?
Paul: A simple normalization operation.
Paul: So, if you really look into, this is my vector store variable. An np.array, score for underscore, I am passing score in vector results.
Paul: You know, what is the purpose of keeping this underscore?
Paul: Quickly tell me.
Paul: It means that the return type can be two different things, so that's why I'm keeping it blank, I know that.
Paul: Alright, a pretty much blank one. Now, in the next step, normalizing the scores. Now, this is the part, so vector score is equal to 1 minus
Paul: Vector score minus np.mean, or vector score divided by np.max, vector store minus np.mean plus epsilon. Can you see here this epsilon?
Paul: This is in the… denominator part. That was the mean purpose, so that it doesn't become zero.
Paul: Okay.
Paul: Now, here, this is much more towards your mean and max normalization that I told you about. And finally, here, you have your BM25 scores. Now, for this, the mean max
Paul: Core part. Now, this is your core vector store. It means that this particular preprocessing that you are just performing on top of your dens.
Paul: Now, in the next step, coming to your BM25 sports. In BM25, the calculations will be easier. Why? Because there will be a lot of zero, but in vector store, the calculation really takes time, because
Paul: There are no zeros. Everything will be based on float values.
Paul: So that's what I'm telling you. So, when you will be actually doing this particular line will take more time for your execution, and this will be taking lesser time, because most values will be, pretty much within that zero part.
Paul: That's the formula, Sean.
Paul: All right, now coming to, the BM25, so this is the pure mean and max normalization that I have taken into account. There is nothing. If you really look into this one, and this one.
Paul: How many of you understand? Because if you really look into this formula, it's the same. Here, just, I have taken 1 minus.
Paul: If you really look into this formula and this formula, it's pretty much the same.
Paul: It's pure normalization operation that I am doing.
Paul: In both the cases, the formula remains the same, there is no difference.
Paul: Now, combining the scores. Now, this is where the core thing that comes around.
Paul: Generally, see, Al, to combine, see, Modaza, both of the reserves are in a different scale. The idea is to bring them to a single scale.
Paul: That's why that normalization operation is done.
Paul: Now, in the next step, combining the scores, combined scores is equal to this alpha parameter, again, which is a hyperparameter. For now, I've taken 0.5.
Paul: You might work with 0.6, 0.7, 0.4, but don't go very close to 1.
Paul: Okay, so here you can see the weight for the vector store, so 1 minus alpha will be the weight of the BM25 score. So generally, I feel that it should be around 0.4, 0.5, 0.6. These are around sleep limits. Don't go very close to 0, neither go very close to 1.
Paul: Now, this is the same thing that I have written, so alpha into the vector server plus 1 minus alpha into. Now, if you really look into alpha and 1 minus alpha.
Paul: Now, when you look into this formula, what you can think about?
Paul: Tell me, somewhere you might have seen this formula.
Paul: Alpha is a balancing act, correct. 1 is correct, inversely proportional,
Paul: Alright, smoothening formula. Yes, correct, this is a smoothening formula. John, we're pretty much correct. I was actually looking for that term, weighted average.
Paul: Okay, it means that, yes, you guys know at least that one. Yes, that is fine. Like, I was actually looking for, like, generally, in weighted average, if you learned about beta.
Paul: Okay, beta with 1 minus beta.com. Correct. Weighted average was the exact term.
Paul: Okay, now, this is the part, okay, and…
Paul: Corely, if I, say the value of alpha, if you try to increase this one.
Paul: Okay, so for example, if you take alpha 0.9, Who will have more dominance?
Paul: When you look into this formula.
Paul: Viraj is selling sparse, how? If you pass here, alpha value, let's take 0.9. And here, 1 minus 0.9. Who will be getting much more focus? Vector store.
Paul: So always keep that balance, so that's why I picked up 0.5 here.
Paul: Just to maintain that balance. I hope everybody understands it now.
Paul: Yes, the idea is to maintain the balance. Sometimes, that's why I told 0.
Paul: 6 you can make it, it means that the focus will be much more on this side. If you make 0.4, it means that the focus will be much more towards your sparse vector. That's why.
Paul: Alright, now, in the next step that comes is basically, ranking the documents. This is nothing related to re-ranking. This is simple rank operation through arc sort that we are doing it here.
Paul: And now, finally, I'll be returning the top K documents that I'll be getting from the sorted indexes.
Paul: Okay, now, this is a pure, like, scratch implementation that I'm showing you.
Paul: So, if anybody asks you how we are doing the combination of the both vector stores.
Paul: This is the core part. Now, you cannot combine directly. It means that direct merge operation is not performed. Both the scales, first of all, needs to be normalized, then only you can perform that. And if you really think about it, this is pretty much a weighted average operation.
Paul: Yes, correct, Deva.
Paul: Now, when we solve our optimization pricing agent to calculate the true alpha, okay?
Paul: Alright, you can, try it out, there is no issue. So, first of all, let's define it. Now, this is a poor function, guys. There is nothing other. Now, this one, directly, I will define it here. Okay? I hope I have made pretty much clear the first part, this entire thing.
Paul: Alright. Now, so basically, you're combining the scores, not the vector itself.
Paul: Correct. We are right now, everywhere, focusing on this particular scores. The entire game is based on scores.
Paul: Now, in the next part, with respect to this fusion retrieval data will come.
Paul: Now, here's… first of all, you have this one, okay, I've already told you this part.
Paul: So use case example, that's why, okay?
Paul: Now, I will be passing any query, and I'll be directly calling this one DevFusionRetrieval.
Paul: Okay, the top talks with respect to fission deductible, the vector scoot that I'm passing the VM25 query k is equal to 5 alpha, okay? So, here…
Paul: Okay, so right now, if you really look into this particular, like.
Paul: What are the impacts of climate change on the environment? Legality and responsibilities coming.
Paul: Some context, because right now.
Paul: Total, 5 will come as I have, the written type here, query K.
Paul: is equal to 5 data have passed. Now, if you simply change this parameter of alpha, okay, so for example, if I make it, let's put 0.8.
Paul: 0.8 means what… on which side the main focus will be.
Paul: 0.8, it means that I'm giving more focus to what?
Paul: Always remember that, okay, whenever you are playing with this fusion regimen.
Paul: Can you see here? The output got changed?
Paul: Always remember that.
Paul: If you play with those parameters, though, the idea is always to maintain a balance. If I make a 0.2, really, we don't…
Paul: The idea is always to give
Paul: 60-70% priority to your vector store, and 20-30% priority to that.
Paul: to your, sparse vector. Okay, so here, if I again change…
Paul: Something with respect to, again, you can see, the results are actually changing.
Paul: No?
Paul: This operation with respect to scores, these are referred to as score fusion operationals.
Paul: Yes, BM25 scores higher, the better, correct, in this particular context.
Paul: Okay? Alright.
Paul: Now, this, part I have gone. Now, I will, try to show you a few…
Paul: Other implementations also, because few line chain part also that I have taken into account.
Paul: Now, in Langchain, this is much more fusion, you have to understand. I am focusing much more on scoot, that's why the name comes with respect to Fusion Retriever, because you are playing with the scores much more.
Paul: Now, a little bit with respect to Langchain, because directly in Langchain, the core objective is different.
Paul: Can you try with Splate? Yes, you can try, there is no issue with that, sir. You can do your own implementation with Splate.
Paul: Alright, now, here comes,
Paul: With respect to land chain, okay, so…
Paul: I think… new things, really, I don't think there is something new. One thing can be new, which is the assembled Retriever.
Paul: Okay, now, this, retriever, comes from Lansing, like, it is one of the advanced retrievers through which you can attach multiple retrievers, the name Ensemble. I hope everybody understands Ensemble in machine learning.
Paul: Vipen is asking, what is fusion? That's the fusion, the sparse and the vector. When two things mix, that is referred to as fusion within.
Paul: Okay? Multiple models, correct? Now, a very similar approach that I'll be taking here.
Paul: Now, through the ensemble Retriever, I will try to attach two different types of retrievers, okay? Now, loading the PDF…
Paul: Split into chunks.
Paul: Okay, so here's splitting. Now, this is your dense retrieval implementation.
Paul: Tense writable, that's what we are referring to as semantic.
Paul: I think everybody should be familiar.
Paul: See, guys, the syntax, you guys have seen this syntax more than now, I feel, 20 to 30 times.
Paul: Alright.
Paul: Huh? Alright. Now, here in the next step.
Paul: Again, so from here, 3, from here, 3, if you really look into it. So, this is the sparse retriever that I have defined.
Paul: Now, this is a, again, this particular retriever is also based on your Okabe 25mm.
Paul: Okay, so, simply.
Paul: So, in our previous examples, we never defined the sparse vector, but this time, very specifically, we're defining the sparse. Now, the question comes in which cases sparse, and what is the main use case of using a sparse vector?
Paul: In hybrid search. It means that when your semantic search fails.
Paul: Somehow, it is not able to find the correct context. In that case, you can do a simpler, simplest keyword matching.
Paul: Which sparse vectors can do. In the last class also, I've told you, that is the main core purpose.
Paul: Of building both solutions.
Paul: Now, on top of this, You can add much more customized keyword searching algorithms also.
Paul: It can be a fallback. It means that if this doesn't work, if this doesn't work, and this doesn't work.
Paul: So sometimes, yes, custom algorithms also, they come into the picture, where you have a set of dictionary.
Paul: through that custom, like I can say, based on your knowledge base, you'll be creating certain phrases, which will actually help you to make your search much more faster.
Paul: Okay, so custom implementations also, sometimes my… you can look into, I've seen, generally, in domain-specific fields, they try to build that knowledge base.
Paul: So here, this is a simple implementation of our BM25 Retriever. Now see.
Paul: First of all, what I have done, my hybrid retina. Now, this is where both the things, I'll be passing it.
Paul: Can you see here? See, I am not writing this 0.5, 0.5, the weightage.
Paul: Now, this weightage definition, when I'm telling you, so what does it represent? Quickly tell me.
Paul: When you say 0.5, so what is the meaning of 0.5 here?
Paul: Alpha, alpha, alpha, that is the meaning. It's not equal priority, it means that the alpha value that we are setting. So that's why that weightage parameter that comes.
Paul: Alright.
Paul: Then my LLM initialization, creating a rag chain. Okay, from chain, I am passing the retriever to my hybrid retriever. Most of the times, we have done this thing only.
Paul: And return source document is equal to true for now.
Paul: Then, I'm just invoking the chain, as simple as that. So, what is the main topic of the document that I am passing? And based on that, we are printing out the result and the context.
Paul: Now, this result will change if you change the…
Paul: context. So, most of the times, because here, both the values need to be changed manually, so it's a good practice, give a variable.
Paul: Okay, like an alpha variable, and passed that alpha and 1 minus alpha. In that way, you can directly change that alpha parameter, and you can actually see the change with respect to the result that you'll be getting.
Paul: Because right now, I've given equal weightage, but if you actually change this, parameter.
Paul: Okay, so… and don't give less weightage to your dense vector, always remember, you should have equal or higher preference to your dense vector, and you should give lesser preference to your sparse vector.
Paul: Yes, you can give more to death. So generally, like, if I will be… so this particular weights parameter, probably I'll be defining in somewhere alpha here. I think I can take from my previous implementation.
Paul: Somewhere around here. Alpha is equal to 0.5.
Paul: And so, let's pause it here.
Paul: Okay, do this implementation, this is much more cleaner implementation, I feel. Okay?
Paul: I hope the different implementation using long-term vision implementation, I hope different implantation.
Paul: implementation, I think, using language and fusion rating implementation. Yes, the idea, I see, I take custom implementation, just to show you.
Paul: Okay. Now, I'll be coming to much more other things also, because the idea was to first give you a focus towards the fusion retribut. Now, similarly, things are there in Llama Index also.
Paul: Okay, it means that two different types that you can actually pass it out. So here, there is a direct approach through hybrid. Now, this is a very high-level approach, where you can directly define.
Paul: So, this approach also, if you want, because in our Llama Index part, we have taken that. So, here, vector store query mode. So, generally, most of the times, this query mode, direct hybrid retriever, just by adding on top of your query engine.
Paul: This is much more high-level implementation as compared to your land check, but the same thing that remains here also. So, here, automatically, everything is calculated. You don't need to do anything manually. I feel this implementation is much better, but you have to understand the core implementation, exactly why it happens.
Paul: Okay, so test it out. Okay, so let's go for a break. What's the time right now? 10.48. Now I will be coming to that a little bit towards, spars and other things.
Paul: Okay? So, till now, what I have discussed, please let me know that you guys are comfortable with the core concept.
Paul: Okay, now, simply say, if I try to get that, part, okay, so let's get back here. I will take to… take that particular image, I will just stop sharing. In the notes, I will paste it, because this is with this particular implementation only.
Paul: Alright, so first of all, let's take the combination of this course. I will get back here.
Paul: Advanced to the BitWAC cable.
Paul: Alright. Now, the same thing that I have written, rather than writing, let me just get the combination of both.
Paul: The first part that comes.
Paul: Okay, so going forward, always remember the flow that we have. This is the same flow that you need to talk with respect to in your interviews also, so that's why
Paul: I'm just… Pasting the flow here. The same flow that is written in code.
Paul: Okay, two things that came into the picture. Okay, and finally, my main ragflow, so for that, let me get this one.
Paul: Okay, now this is your full one.
Paul: Now, in the start part.
Paul: Now, the same thing with respect to, first of all, combination of the scores and normalizing the scores.
Paul: So, first of all, you have to understand, okay, let me bring combine later on, so that it becomes much easier. Okay?
Paul: So, generally, the normalization that I have taken for both the operations, then I have done that particular combination operation. So, in your RAC pipeline, the first part, get all documents for vector store. Now, here, you have to think about, whenever you are doing this vector such, it means that you have the context.
Paul: You have both the things, can I say you have your score and the context?
Paul: It means that you are actually not doing operation on top of the… your context is setting, and you are actually playing only with the sports. It means that you are not changing that context. Just remember that this is very important.
Paul: AP.
Paul: You have to understand, whenever in our code also.
Paul: When you are doing the core implementation, it means that you are actually playing with the scores, not with the context. The context remains the same, because through that score, you will be performing that ranking operation.
Paul: Is this part clear?
Paul: Viraj… why Viraj is asking, why we are retrieving all the documents for vector store, rather than just retrieving…
Paul: When similar… we aren't retrieving similar dogs, Virat.
Paul: C.
Paul: here we are, when I'm telling that you are performing this. So, this place, you are actually performing that retrieval operation.
Paul: Here, I am retrieving the similar docs.
Paul: So, what is the value of all talks coming? Just check.
Paul: K is equal to length of all docs that I have written, so what is the value?
Paul: In our core implementation, if I try to get that particular value, if you are asking me, Hmm…
Paul: Because that one… Tokenize your tweet.
Paul: Is there a way we always to find top K chunks? Is there a way we do always? That's the job of the Retriever.
Paul: Whoever is asking, is it… Okay, always remembered that.
Paul: Dig Vijay?
Paul: How do we combine the scores? Now, this is the part through which you are performing the combination operation, the same formula that I have written it in the notebook also.
Paul: Now the question… first, normalization. If you don't perform a normalized operation, then actually we'll be getting error.
Paul: Now, with VM25 as an adhesion to the vectors are correct. Now, the idea is how to improve that.
Paul: Okay, now, that's fine. So let's take a break, guys, and then, I think. Because the idea was to show you the flow also, that's why I'll be keeping it notes for your later part that you can, simply refer it to.
Paul: Okay, so let's go for a break. Everyone, do your breakfast, and then we will be back.
Paul: Alrighty, Waz, I hope everyone is back.
Paul: Perfect.
Paul: barrage.
Paul: Yes, Viraj, so you can understand all things refer to the chunks, basically, the total chunks.
Paul: So watch is asking, can we do this implementation where we might do the generator?
Paul: the purpose of Heidi to generate a dense query embedding correct, Heidi will, actually… Si su vaz.
Paul: We don't use IT to generate a query embedding, you have to understand that.
Paul: We use Heidi to generate a document.
Paul: First of all, get that…
Paul: Okay, alright, now you are telling retrieving the dens by doing a similar against the hypoten, correct.
Paul: Okay, that part.
Paul: Yes, the intuition is correct, Subhash, that you have told.
Paul: Alright, now we're out. Now, guys, let's focus a little bit towards the sparse part, okay? Now, this part I want, everyone to focus.
Paul: Why? Because the idea is that BM25 is not highly optimized.
Paul: Okay, like, the idea is that in today's world, we have transformers. So, the idea is, why not?
Paul: Let's look into that part also.
Paul: I'll write a widget, I can do that, okay?
Paul: So let's focus… I have another notebook, just to focus on. Now, always remember, going forward in your hybrid search.
Paul: you have two things, the sparse vector and the tense. Intense vector really
Paul: there, whichever type of embedding model that you are using, okay, it is responsible, okay, probably OpenAI, okay, another from Koha, BGM, those type of models, it's fine. But.
Paul: The idea is that only, let's focus on sparse, because going forward, I feel that somehow it will be improved.
Paul: Then, this part, less improvement I have seen, people are actually focusing on that sparse part. So, little bit, let's focus on that sparse part now.
Paul: So the idea is to bring something from static towards…
Paul: Learning. That concept of learning, we will try to bring it.
Paul: Okay, so let's get here our desktop 2.
Paul: Alright, and I think you have on this one. Okay, so… this part… okay, this advanced part's embedded.
Paul: This will be talking about.
Paul: Right now.
Paul: So, few things that needs to be, installed in your system. Just be sure you guys have done the installation, I've already given the commands. You can do it from here also. Now, I have taken an implementation, from PyMilverse. Okay, so that's why this time I'll be changing my…
Paul: I can say the vector database. Okay, so this time I'll be using Milverse. I think Milverse is a very good
Paul: Like, my favorites are, Milbos and Quadrant.
Paul: So, for now, I've taken that particular implementation. RRF, I will come to that part, don't worry.
Paul: I will come.
Paul: This entire… because right now, the focus only will be on hybrid search.
Paul: I did, my hypothetical generals, I added,
Paul: Meta for a retrieval, but it was very costly, and latency was high, yet the results were awesome.
Paul: But it was a bit close. Alright, ma'am, it can depend, really. Like, I'm not telling that it's, always one, but I feel that somehow it gives that 10-12% added advantage on top of the retrieval.
Paul: The operation will be costly, because you are adding that particular information to every chunk metadata.
Paul: For better retrieval, alright.
Paul: Because if you are doing that operation on top of every chunk, for sure, that will be costly.
Paul: On top of each chunk, probably I can do a different operation. Okay, you are actually saving it in the metadata. Find the approach. There's one level of added filtering that you can do through metadata.
Paul: Alright, guys, so, first of all, let's proceed, okay, and now I'll be talking about a particular topic called as Splat, S-P-L-A-D, okay? So, for now, please do the installation, and later on, like, I will be, taking this into account.
Paul: Okay, so a few things are here.
Paul: Clean up and other things, all right.
Paul: So let's get into notes, okay, and let's try to understand our new approach for our sparse embedding generation.
Paul: I've put firmware came in, alright.
Paul: Okay, so, let's start with, splat part.
Paul: No, There is a research paper, okay, and it has multiple added iterations also.
Paul: So, like, you have… The first one.
Paul: main focus… will be.
Paul: better… Quality.
Paul: parse vector.
Paul: Okay? How we can achieve that. Now, for example, if you are taking BM25,
Paul: Okay, so if I'm talking about TF, IDM, or VM25, any algorithm that you can tick, TF idea film.
Paul: Now, what is the, my core underlying thing.
Paul: Can I say that these type of algorithm, whether it's TF, or BM25.
Paul: How it works.
Paul: it take two main factors, okay? Whenever you are working with. The first of all, the first thing that comes is the document length.
Paul: And what is the second?
Paul: Keyword.
Paul: And generally, there is a saturation term, I can say, with respect to your entire vocabulary size that comes. So, I will say keyword saturation term.
Paul: These two things comes, like, as, like, BM25 is the enhancement of TAFIDM, in simple terms, but both of the algorithms state these two factors.
Paul: Now, the question comes, they work on exact keyword matching.
Paul: Can I say that they work on exact keywords matching, yes or no?
Paul: Okay, now the question comes, if the keyword match fails, then what will happen?
Paul: Because when the exact match of the query, keyword, for example, whatever the user will pass the query based on that, you are trying, actually, to look into the keyword, but it's not…
Paul: It could not be found. Can I say that the sparse vector of BM25 or of TFIDM will, try to fail?
Paul: In simple terms.
Paul: Okay, now the question comes that, these are all static.
Paul: Static means based on a… Simple formula.
Paul: Based on some formula that you are actually generating.
Paul: Now, the question comes… How?
Paul: to move this static part and try to bring something from Transformers' perspective.
Paul: Okay, because the core thing from BM25, right now, we'll move towards something called as SP.
Paul: split.
Paul: Now, when I'm talking with respect to split, okay, now, from the static, we will try to move towards learnable.
Paul: Because that's the job of entire… Deep learning, machine learning, everywhere.
Paul: Okay? Now, how to make it somehow learnable? Now, the question comes, for sure, we'll be using some type of transformers. And majorly, false flat, like BERT has been used. Okay, BERT is the core architecture.
Paul: On top of which it has been built. It means that we'll be using the core architecture of BERT.
Paul: Now, the first step. So, in BERT, one… what is the major capability of BERT? Like, in what type of task we use BERT?
Paul: Yes, guys, please let me know.
Paul: There is something called as MLM.
Paul: BERT is also referred to as MLN.
Paul: Context understanding, nothing Ankush like that. Dig Vijay, understanding task, again, nothing.
Paul: Like that. MLM. How many of you know about MLM?
Paul: Correct.
Paul: MLM stands for masked.
Paul: Language model.
Paul: So, whenever there is a masking task, so what type of things? Token classification is one good example, correct?
Paul: For example, fill in the blanks.
Paul: predicting the next word in the sequence, so generally fill in the blanks when I refer, it means that predicting the next word in the sequence.
Paul: Okay? Now, we will try to use BERT, okay? And using BERT, we will try to generate.
Paul: The idea is to get the capability of this BERTS MLM for the generation of sparse vector.
Paul: So, we will move towards learnable sparse vector.
Paul: From static, we will move to learnable, because at least we know that it will be better.
Paul: Now, the question comes. So, first of all, what do you have to do?
Paul: to do, these type of applications. The first step is
Paul: The first process always comes with a tokenization operation.
Paul: Whether it's bot, whether it's GPT.
Paul: You have to, tokenize the document Yes?
Paul: And you'll be having some type of query with you. So generally, most of the times, you'll be having the query.
Paul: Another question comes?
Paul: The query that you have.
Paul: That query… you have to look into a sub-word level tokenization. Okay, now…
Paul: With the query, you will be looking into a…
Paul: Subword label tokenization. Now, this is what really, like, if you are actually, like, anybody has done a complete fine-tuning of what.
Paul: In NLP. If you have done this, then this particular operation, you generally do it.
Paul: Okay? So, it's a common one, like, subvert label tokenization process, input that we do.
Paul: Now, this particular puzzle.com. So, Splat will employ this particular approach. So, Splat actually uses this
Paul: Particular approach for generating your sparse token.
Paul: Okay, now the question comes, through the query, you will try to predict the most preferable token.
Paul: Okay, the idea is true.
Paul: predict.
Paul: Duh.
Paul: Most… preferable token.
Paul: And this is what Bird is really good at.
Paul: Like, anything, because it's… the core prediction that comes through MLM.
Paul: Now, most of the time, the words… vocabulary size, okay, so…
Paul: Anybody remember what is the vocabulary size of Bert?
Paul: Yes, close to 30,000.
Paul: Okay, so this is the general one. BERT has multiple ones.
Paul: Split users MLA mameth.
Paul: An MLM comes from both.
Paul: Yes, it's close to 30K, so I'm just writing that, like, 3522 is the most common number.
Paul: Okay?
Paul: Now, if I'm talking about, can I say that this is the entire, like, the… context of the…
Paul: Entire sequence.
Paul: That comes around here.
Paul: Okay, the idea is to predict the most preferable tokens, okay? From Worth's vocabulary, which is, like, 30,000,
Paul: Okay, and we'll be considering the context of the entire sequence. Entire sequence means the sequence comes from your actual data, so your entire data is broken into multiple sequences in both.
Paul: Now, the idea is that we will try to combine these functionalities. So, Splat will basically combine
Paul: the return type, so whenever you are predicting anything, it will come with the probability. Okay, so the Splat will try to combine the probabilities.
Paul: Okay? For each token, like, whatever the token in the next sequence that will come? Because the most preferable token, it means a prediction.
Paul: For the next token in the sequence. So for that, you'll be getting the probability, that is the return time.
Paul: Okay.
Paul: And…
Paul: Once we have this particular probability across all the positions of the sequence that we'll be getting through from our data, the mean, and write out the data, you can take about the core vocab. Now, what is vocabulary? Vocabulary refers to the
Paul: What is vocabulary, guys? If I say that the vocabulary is 13, what is the meaning of that? Quickly tell me in the chat.
Paul: Vocabulary refers always to the unique.
Paul: Okay.
Paul: 13 words…
Paul: 13 words, I could not get that, okay, 30K unique words. That's the core intuition that you have to take, okay? Now to… now, through spread, okay, we'll be combining the, probabilities
Paul: Okay, across each token.
Paul: Okay?
Paul: Now, generally, your core, part, because here, the core…
Paul: Now, BERT is based on which architecture? Quickly tell me.
Paul: Pertails based on which architecture?
Paul: Decoder or encoder?
Paul: It's encoder only.
Paul: Okay.
Paul: Through Encoder, actually, we parse this information.
Paul: Okay, free people are telling Decoder, no, not decoder, it's purely encoder, guys, okay?
Paul: Now, transformer, encoder blocks that you will have, now there can be multiple blocks.
Paul: Now, as you know, that BERT has different variants also.
Paul: Yes? What are the different variants of BERT, guys?
Paul: Quickly, tell me.
Paul: One has a 12, and the other one is 24.
Paul: Okay, 12 and 24.
Paul: If you remembered that.
Paul: Variants… no, no, no, I'm talking about the Kurbata myth. I'm not referring to robata, distalbot, those things. Okay, I'm talking about the core birth, two different variants it had.
Paul: Okay? Okay.
Paul: Now,
Paul: Here, we are talking with respect to bot small only, we are not talking with respect to bot large.
Paul: Now, what we'll be doing? So, if we take, any type of token, okay, probably a sequence will come. Through that sequence, you will try to predict the most preferable token.
Paul: Now, multiple sequences can also come from your data. Through that, for every sequence, that you will always try to get the most preferable token.
Paul: Okay, now, preferable word when I used. Okay, so this prefer also you might…
Paul: Get confused. So, prefer… so, what is the preference here?
Paul: Preference refers to…
Paul: probable. Okay, like, the one with the highest probability, because I know that I refer to that highest probabil token only, that it will be predicting.
Paul: So…
Paul: Once your bot will throw you these probabilities across each token, okay? And then we'll be applying a logarithmic saturation. Now, this thing that comes important.
Paul: Logarithmic saturation that take place.
Paul: Okay? Now, through logarithmic saturation, okay, we try to introduce sparsity.
Paul: Now…
Paul: If you really look into this particular case, how many of you think that probabilities… a lot of probabilities, like, in your main vector, there will be a lot of zeros? How many of you think?
Paul: How many of you think that in your sparse vector, there will be a lot of zeros?
Paul: It means that the core logic of having zeros
Paul: It will remain, it means that it will be constant.
Paul: But, as I'm talking about the dimension, because the vocabulary size has really increased this time, for example, the bird vocabulary size.
Paul: It means that, can I say that my dimension will increase?
Paul: Like, your sparse vector dimension.
Paul: Like, 32, 5, 72… okay. It can be much more optimized, like, at least it will be towards the higher side, like, it can be sometimes close to 3,000, 4,000. Most of the times in production, when we're working, we take something around, like, 10,000 to 30,000.
Paul: Okay, higher the number of dimensions, just remember that the cost will increase.
Paul: Okay, so that is the only… so always think about that dimension parameter. For example, if you have taken any third-party service, they will charge you per vector basis. Okay, it doesn't matter. Okay, so per vector with dimension, these two things really matter.
Paul: Now, you are saving your delvector. There are nothing we can do.
Paul: Okay? So, there nothing we can do, but what… here, we'll be changing that dimension. It means that every time, 30,522, it means that if it is not built on top of BERT, if you're using a different variant of BERT, okay, we might change it.
Paul: This particular dimension, because somehow this 30,000… how many of you feel that 30,000 dimension is high?
Paul: Please let me know.
Paul: 30,000 dimension is high.
Paul: Actually, 30,000 dimension is not high, guys. In NLP,
Paul: It's really low, okay? The dimensions are much higher, generally. Okay, just think about a book. In that book, if I ask you in a novel, how many unique words you will get.
Paul: you can think about that number can be much higher. It totally depends upon the length of the book, for sure, the length of your corpus, but that number can be much higher always.
Paul: Alright. Now, through your logarithmic saturation, we will try to introduce data sparsity.
Paul: Because we need to bring data sparsity into the picture, otherwise.
Paul: Bert is not good in that.
Paul: Okay, so that's why a logarithmic saturation, and actually that saturation on top of your, like, tokens that we try to apply here.
Paul: BPE has around, correct, 50K vocabulary.
Paul: Now, the final weights that we'll be getting, okay, from BERT, okay, and majorly, it will be the probabilities of the token. So, therefore, we call this a learnable sparse vector. Okay, so from here, that's why we call it a
Paul: Learnable.
Paul: path vector.
Paul: Okay, and the core objective, in simple terms, it means that we parse that information.
Paul: Okay, so it means that the data that you'll be passing, it will be broken into sequences, that sequence as you'll be passing through that sequence as you'll be looking into the most preferable token in that particular sequence.
Paul: Now, when you pass something through the transformers, What it gets.
Paul: Can I say somehow better context?
Paul: At least, because… If you move something from static to learnable, can I say that it is somehow better
Paul: Rather than using a direct formula and getting that.
Paul: See, really, the improvement, okay, and I'll be talking about, because in multiple papers, I have seen that it's not necessary that speed will always help you.
Paul: Okay. Now, I will come to that, because the core, paper of Splat that comes into the picture, we'll be looking into that, and then we'll be looking into the implementation.
Paul: Now, the default flat version that you have, it is trained on MS Marco. How many of you know about MS Marco?
Paul: MS Marco dataset.
Paul: MS Marco, MS Marco?
Paul: Alright, so that is a widely used dataset which has been used, so…
Paul: Let me get back to the paper of Splat, first of all.
Paul: No, really…
Paul: If you want to use flat in your implementation, it's pretty much direct call, but the idea was to explain you how to bring that learnable concept
Paul: Through encoder of input.
Paul: Now, don't worry about that, because in your implementation, it'll be pretty much direct.
Paul: So, first of all, let me take Desktop 2. Now, this is much more, towards architecture level, I can say.
Paul: So, a ladder paper that you have.
Paul: Okay.
Paul: Okay, now this paper was introduced back in July 2021.
Paul: Okay, so as you can see, SPLAT, Water stands for Sparse Lexical and Expansion Model for
Paul: first stage ranking, okay, as the name suggests. Now, let's try to go through the abstract and what they are trying to say, and how it is, like.
Paul: beneficial.
Paul: So, in information retrieval, ongoing research is directed towards improving first-stage retriever in ranking pipelines. So, now the question comes, what is a first-stage retriever, and what are two-stage retrievals? Anybody has any idea?
Paul: Yes, with respect to multiple, retrieval stages that you have.
Paul: Please let me know.
Paul: Otherwise, I have to show you one another document.
Paul: Yes.
Paul: Hmm, which stage is re-ranking? Not exactly re-ranking.
Paul: No ideology's fine, I think. There is one…
Paul: The lead that comes from pine congestion.
Paul: This is a good vlog, actually, if you want to get through this.
Paul: Alright, now, I'm just quickly going through this, okay, and I'm sharing the link in the chat if you really want to deep dive into this one.
Paul: Okay, okay. Now, first of all, in this blog, they have told about sparse and dense. What are the pros and cons? Okay, so those things. Like, for sparse, what are the pros? These things you can go. Now, first comes a two-stage retrieval process.
Paul: Now, two stage…
Paul: retrievals. Generally, it takes more time as compared to a single-stage retrieval. Now, here you can see the architecture. So, they are talking about a typical approach to handling this implementation of two-stage retrieval and a ranking system, is to use two distinct stages. One is to retrieve, one is to rank.
Paul: So, generally, the idea is if you can retrieve and rank in one shot.
Paul: Okay, so first of all, retrieve and rank the documents for a given query.
Paul: So, this is how your first stage, the system uses a sparse retrieval method to retrieve a large set of candidate documents. Now, this is a simple retrieval algorithm.
Paul: And generally, it consists of DP. Here, it can be, like, SPR-based, parse, passage retrieval techniques which are used.
Paul: These are passed to the second stage, when we use a dense model to re-rank the results, based on the relevance to the query. Can you see, first of all, they are talking about the sparse part, then they are talking about the dense part.
Paul: For two levels.
Paul: How many of you got it now, when I tell about a two-stage ranking systems?
Paul: Yes?
Paul: The first stage is basically the sparse retriever. On top of that, actually, you take the DELS.
Paul: One into the picture.
Paul: This is not typical hybrid search. In hybrid search, it is not necessary always that you will first doing a sparse retriever. You can do a dense retriever also, muddhasur.
Paul: Okay, now, generally, like, this is how it looks like, if you want to really go…
Paul: Correct, Murthaza. First, looking into the keywords, actually. It will try to perform that, a keyword-based operation, and then it will try to look for a semantic search.
Paul: Okay, got it. Now, this is how it looks like. Now, the idea is to bring something like this. Single-stage systems.
Paul: It means that combining both the things into one shot.
Paul: Okay? Now, through Splat, actually, we'll be doing it. So, if you really look into the idea behind sparse, lexical and expansion models, is that a pre-trained language model like BERT can identify connections between words and subwords. Okay, so generally, like, through your tokens, it can get better context, you already know that.
Paul: And we can use that knowledge to enhance our sparse embedding model. I told you to bring the parameter of learning. Okay, so…
Paul: Now, it has told about few of the things with respect to, like, a few examples if you really want to go through. But, really with respect to… we are focused much on towards splayed embeddings. So, in split embeddings, this particular concept I have already told you about MLM,
Paul: So MLM is a typical pre-training method used by transformers, okay? So we can start.
Paul: of the shelf with a direct pre-trained BERT model.
Paul: So, if you want at any point of time… okay, so first of all, they are talking about, let's take a piece of text, let's convert them into tokens, convert islets into tokens based on that particular implementation.
Paul: Now, token embeddings.
Paul: with an embedding matrix, and finally passing. Now, this is much more towards the bird-based architecture, rather than towards it. And finally, the learnables pass vectors, okay? Somehow, you will feel that they will be closer to your dense vector as compared to your static
Paul: sparse vector.
Paul: Okay, I can say close. I won't say very close also, but somehow close.
Paul: So, in that way, I feel that it's better in somehow. So, this is part, but really, like, if you don't know BERT, it becomes harder to explain the internal code details. So, at any point of time, if you want, please go through that BERT, concept once. It becomes easier, and then you can actually go through that.
Paul: particular block. Because right now, our main implementation will be with respect to the consumption of Slack directly.
Paul: So, the core logic behind.
Paul: The idea is to move from static
Paul: Sparse embeddings to somehow learnable sparse embeddings.
Paul: And we will be using it through Stone.
Paul: Is this part clear?
Paul: Are these probabilities are calculated using softmax function? Yes, softmax will be there, so…
Paul: Softmax will be there for sure.
Paul: Alright, now, if you want, really, to go understand, because this is exactly with respect to the
Paul: But I feel this is a good plug if you really want to go inside and much more, look into the implementation, okay? Now, this is a COCO emitter, so there are multiple SPLAT versions. There is Splat
Paul: The core version, then you have a V2, V2++, V3… okay, so right now, in 2020, 2024, you have this flat V3 version, which really works good. And they are directly available from Hugging Face, so you really do need to worry about… so if I show you the models, Hugging…
Paul: Faith?
Paul: Vlad.
Paul: Okay, so here you can see.
Paul: This is a V3 version. Okay, in that blog, they have given the core version. Okay, you can see, split 3 latest series of split. Now, I know that, others will come, so you can always keep a track, like, which one is really good, and if you really look into the returnable-based metrics of MMR and NDJC,
Paul: Yeah, really, like, I know that these are better as compared to the coarse flat.
Paul: Alright, now, the idea is to take this model, and to do the NBD.
Paul: So, let's take the model.
Paul: And directly, we can do an embedding on top of that.
Paul: So, first of all, guys, everybody, please do the installation of the package, because right now we'll be jumping into the practical part.
Paul: Now, previous to this, how many of you knew about Splat, really?
Paul: Because I… in the chat, only one or two people told her.
Paul: Yes, before that.
Paul: Because Plaid is, like, widely used. You have to always think about each component you have to update with respect to time.
Paul: So, like, going forward after 2 years, you have to always correct that Splat 3 can, like, Splat 4 can come, Splat 5 can come, similarly, completely, entirely, Splat has been replaced by a other learnable parse vector generation.
Paul: Okay.
Paul: Alright, fine, like,
Paul: I hope you are getting the idea why I'm teaching this plan, because the idea is to move from static to learnable stuff.
Paul: Alright, so let's focus on this one. Everybody please check, because here a few new things are there.
Paul: So, please have a check on that.
Paul: everybody, because I think the first part is getting the inputs, okay? I think I have kept Nijali here.
Paul: Yes, web install upgrade, PyBilverse model is there, matplotlibone, NLTK, and DatasetCS is there.
Paul: So, please do the installation, because from datasets, I'll be taking a package, the climate fever dataset.
Paul: Okay, and these are some, things with respect to malware. So, right now, I think first time, as we are discussing in this course, Pi Milverse. So, pretty much open source, you guys can directly work with pretty much a very good vector database.
Paul: From here, I'm importing Milvis Client, so even you can install it in your system, but I feel that right now, the core version will work pretty good, you won't have any type of issues.
Paul: And our main objective is to take the Splat implementation directly from, pimilvers.
Paul: You can use Core Hugging phase, that is also fine.
Paul: Please check everybody the import section is working or not.
Paul: Meh.
Paul: Yes, it's working for me. Please have a check that everything is working, because some new libraries came into the picture. Please do the installation and let me know in the chat that imports are working.
Paul: In the meantime, let's talk about this particular part. So, every database
Paul: has, I can say, an added, I can say, most of the vector database libraries that you have, okay, they have inbuilt features. I think probably here also, in the Fusion retrieval, I don't remember.
Paul: Have I taken that, yes. So, for example, this is a ChromaDB part. I didn't show you, but, please have a check on this one. In LanChain, directly, like, if you want to apply hybrid search on top of ChromaDB.
Paul: Okay, you can apply that. So, or direct Pinecone integration is also available, where directly you can apply. Similarly, Viviate is also there, because these are based on vector databases, so really, I didn't pin type. But, you can directly take the implementations from the core package.
Paul: Because LangChain support with direct hybrid search. So, it becomes pretty much like Llama Index. With lesser implementation, you can actually get that.
Paul: So, you can have a check on that.
Paul: Okay, so Aarara will come later on, but, for now.
Paul: direct integrations are available, so really, I feel that This part is good.
Paul: And if you want direct-based implementations, in that case, it works. But for now, please have a check and let me know in the chat that, in the advanced fast embeddings.
Paul: Is it working or not?
Paul: For everybody, the import is working.
Paul: took 40 seconds. I think for the first time, it might take towards the higher side, but I think it should work for everybody fine. Alright? Now, in Bibleverse, you have few, like, utility module. Under that, you have multiple utility functions, field schema, so when you are actually designing the schema of a vector database, in that case, that field schema is very important.
Paul: Then, collection schema, generally, through, for the definition of a collection schema, you need that free schema.
Paul: Then you have data type, what type of data type you want to use, then you have your collection. ANN search request, these are search requests for hybrid search. So, they refer their hybrid search as ANN search request.
Paul: Okay, because that dense vector that comes into the picture, because of that, term alienine that comes into the picture. And then we have an, ranker, RHF ranker, I'll be talking about this concept also in theory. And finally, like, connections.
Paul: Okay, so, few things which are available. So, let's start, because right now, our main focus will be towards this particular implementation.
Paul: Because BM25 embedding function, this is what I want to take into account, and Splat embedding function.
Paul: Okay? And then in the next step, I have taken some data set, like the climate fever dataset, one of the most common datasets whenever you are working with NLP-related problems.
Paul: For, plotting, I think Matplotlib, Seaborn, and NumPy, okay, I have a few numerical operations that I'll be taking into account.
Paul: Okay, so let me just import.
Paul: Now, let me load the dataset. Okay, so I am loading the dataset in the first place.
Paul: And right now, from that, corpus, you have your train and test. Right now, I'm just looking into the test, and I'm looking into only one column, okay, which is basically the claims one.
Paul: Printing sample claims from the dataset, okay, and then the length of the entire corpus, I'm just printing it out. So let me just print it out, so that at least a few information that you'll be getting with respect to the dataset.
Paul: So, these are a few sample claims from the dataset, like, global warning is driving polar bears, okay, as I think we have printed close to, yes, fine.
Paul: Now, once we have this particular information… now, in the next step, okay, is,
Paul: We'll try to, bring, because here, these are sentences. The idea is to bring the sentences into tokens. So, in Milverse, you have this build default analyzer through which you can access it. So, generally, for, implementing your sparse, before that, we perform this tokenizer operation in some build terms.
Paul: Now, it's not simple tokenizer, as you can see in the comments I have written, it says tokenizer plus timer.
Paul: What is a stemmer?
Paul: What is a stem app?
Paul: Guide.
Paul: I'm asking him.
Paul: Alright.
Paul: Alright, few people know, okay. Potter No.
Paul: The porter is one type of stemmer, correct?
Paul: Bringing what to the root of what the idea is to get at, okay? What is the alternate of stemming?
Paul: What is the alternate of this statement? Lemmatization, okay? Pretty much classical NLP concept that comes along.
Paul: So, through this build default analyzer, you can actually… so, first of all, here, the language definition, English that I'm doing. Multi-language support is there in Milbus.
Paul: Now, here, directly, I'm passing this VM25 embedding function.
Paul: Okay, and BM25, if fit in here, so this is the initialization, and this is the part with respect to I'm passing the data to our BM25 initializer.
Paul: Now, here, when I execute it…
Paul: Loaded 1535 claims from the dataset total, okay, and the vocabulary size… what is the vocabulary size right now, guys?
Paul: 3, 4, 3, 2.
Paul: Okay, so… Right now, we know that in your vocabulary, these are the actual unique tokens, I can say.
Paul: Alright, now this is the first part that we have done.
Paul: Now, let's take…
Paul: Because we need some type of test document, so that's why random 5 test sentences that I have taken into account. Now, the idea is to encode them, and to perform,
Paul: Similarity, okay. Now, till this part is related to everything VM25. So, I've taken a set of 5 documents.
Paul: Now, this document, I'll be performing an encoding, and what type of encoding? BM25.
Paul: Okay, so let's look at the output till this particular point. So exactly, and then finally comes our, split implementation. So, you can see split embedding function, and here I am passing what is the model.
Paul: Now, this module that I am using, guys, this is the Splate V1. Okay, the older version of Splate. I'm not using the recent one, but you can switch it to the newer version of Splate.
Paul: As simple as that. And I will really suggest, because,
Paul: With respect to getting, generally, it says that more than 15% higher quality sparse embeddings that you will get. Okay, so really, like, you can switch to Splate V3, that even I will suggest, but for now, I've kept the core or the original model from Hugging Face.
Paul: Okay, now a very similar implementation, because I do have the test ones.
Paul: Now, here, a similar, encoding, so here the encoding I'll be performing on top of our split. And finally, let's look into the dimensions here.
Paul: Paul, are these encodings heavy? My kernel crashes after these type of operations. I'm not sure.
Paul: Because it should not crash, it's not very heavy operation also.
Paul: Okay, these type of operations are… common splat can be a bit heavy, but again, the model is not very, very big. Please have a check, guys, because first time, if you execute, this model will take some time to download.
Paul: And if you have a GPU, if you are on Windows, if you have a GPU, and if you have CUDA, please change this CPU to CUDA.
Paul: Okay, it will really impact. In my case, the model was already downloaded in my local machine.
Paul: Okay, so there was no issue. So, initially, for first-time users, it will take some time. I hope everybody… yes, close to 400MB only, it's not a very big mod.
Paul: I think you'll be getting the logs also. For me, I'm not getting the logs. In your case, that, I think progress bars will come.
Paul: Please let me know in the chat, are you guys getting that?
Paul: Because right now, I'm downloading a model from the Hugging Face Model Hub.
Paul: Okay, read to me, yes, you are getting that. Alright, fair.
Paul: Alright, once I download, I should… I don't think it should take a lot of time.
Paul: Okay. Now, based on the 5 test documents that I have passed here, so in simple terms, this document
Paul: I'm encoding in two types. One is the BM25 version, and finally, the splayed version. As simple as that.
Paul: BM25 algorithm is a static algorithm, so directly, that we have taken. But for Splat, I need the model. And you can actually change the model, you can take the Splat V3 also, and you can have a check, because really, I've not tested it, but later on, I'll be showing you that.
Paul: So, first of all, the,
Paul: Prepared 5 documents for our embedding, creating 25. Okay, so example vector shape is 3452. Okay, non-zeros are stored in the sparse format. You can actually print it on… print. And you can get that information. Similarly for Splat, if you really look, what is the dimension of Splat?
Paul: What is the dimension of Splat?
Paul: Guys, repeat.
Paul: These numbers are important, an interview, it is asked.
Paul: If somebody cannot see it, remember, if you… somebody asks you splat, and if you really cannot say it at 30,522, then he or she will know you don't know, but…
Paul: The direct inference. Okay, so that's… if you don't know Splat.
Paul: Okay, and probably if somebody might have given you a hint also, then also you can actually make an inference, so that's why it's very important. Now, can you see the dimension difference?
Paul: What is the dimension difference?
Paul: 10X, at least, let's take 9X. Okay, I will be taking a full number, 10x.
Paul: But really, like, higher dimensions.
Paul: the, I can say that you need, somehow, better infra also to do this operation. It means that it takes more memory as compared to BM25.
Paul: Okay.
Paul: Now, simple ratio 8 to 9 parts, that's why the simple ratio that I have taken into account.
Paul: Now, Milverse, okay.
Paul: The vector database…
Paul: Actually, I was using the core one, so I was planning to use it. Now, can you see here, this is a local implementation? Okay, because I was running Millverse in my local machine, okay, through Docker. I was not doing any installation. So, let's go to that Melliverse page.
Paul: Millworth Install.
Paul: Alright, so I think I have already given you that particular script also.
Paul: Batch standalone restart.
Paul: Docker, Linux… okay, yes, this is a script which is available. Now, this script is for Linux.
Paul: Okay, in WSL also in Windows, it will run in Mac also. This script, if you really look into, I think I've shared this script with you here.
Paul: standalone embed.sh. I actually downloaded it to the script myself, and I have kept it in the repo, okay? So, simply, if you want it, or you can use this command. So, I'm sharing this link in the chat, in whichever way you feel
Paul: No, at least we'll complete this notebook month as well.
Paul: Everybody, please do the setup. As simple as that, like, you have to get this script, pretty much. Once you do a call operation, it will be available in your local machine.
Paul: Okay, so you can see Docker Desktop Windows is there, so you can use that particular option. I've already shared the link with you. So, in which way? In my case, I have used the Linux version. It supports Macs also, so not a problem.
Paul: Please have it checked, guys, everybody.
Paul: Because I know it is working, because yesterday I did the integration with Milibus.
Paul: Previously, you guys have done Docker integration with Vivate, if you remember. This time, Milverse, so let's take, because going forward, we'll be using Milverse and Quadrant a lot in this course.
Paul: It will be… it will go on. I will cover the entire notebook then only.
Paul: Okay, now, the command is there. For me, what I will do, I will take this, okay, so probably, I need to open my Docker, I think, Docker…
Paul: Just open your Docker and just get the script and run it. That is the only basic requirement that you have.
Paul: And, if I'm just doing it, new terminal…
Paul: Okay, so here, that's when I'm gonna start.
Paul: I think it should have been this path only.
Paul: I actually deleted few files. Alright, fine, I will just, delete this one, and let me just take a fresh one.
Paul: I think it should work. Okay? So…
Paul: See, the first command is this one, curl. Okay, just do a copy of this one.
Paul: Okay, so you can see, you will automatically get the script. Once you have the script.
Paul: And in my case, already, I know that, in my case, the container is running, but I will just show you that.
Paul: Alright, so you need to just press these two commands.
Paul: I do have a user.yml, I think. Just wait.
Paul: Please have a check, in your case, it will work.
Paul: Actually, this volume folder that I have, no, it might create a problem with me.
Paul: Just better integrate those volumes further.
Paul: Everybody please do the setup, okay, and let me know that, whether it's working in your system, because in my system, I already have previously tested. So, these two commands that are required.
Paul: Dink.
Paul: Just readily…
Paul: Let me tell you, user.yml also.
Paul: A lot of other folders will be created, so don't worry about that.
Paul: Let me just, delete the container also from here.
Paul: Okay.
Paul: I'm just deleting everything, okay, from mine. I will start with a fresh one.
Paul: So, share that I have… Ctrl plus…
Paul: So, the first thing, I need a curl one, right tutorials, I think.
Paul: ember.sh.
Paul: Okay, so… Little T… That much… one…
Paul: It will be looking something like this in your case. First, the image will be available, and then it will actually try to start.
Paul: Where can I download the installation? Documentation. Documentation. I have shared that.
Paul: That's the idea, you should execute that. So I'm showing you from scratch. Some people might get confused exactly how the logs will look like.
Paul: Alright, fine. If you are… I am able to run the start command from .sh file, correct? If you have that .sh file, that is the same .sh file. I just deleted everything, just showed you, actually, those two commands.
Paul: Okay, similarly for Windows also, if you look, Windows…
Paul: Okay, can you see here? They have a standalone backfile.
Paul: Okay, so using that batch file, you can do.
Paul: So, whichever way. For WSL, I feel that WSL is much better, but if you don't have a WSL, try to use this one. And you can see Docker Administrator, it has to be opened in admin mode, so those things, just be sure for Windows.
Paul: Ankush, great, it's done for you.
Paul: Okay, so…
Paul: You can see here to change the default Milverse configuration, so right now, I won't be doing any changes with respect to the core configuration, okay? And now, if I go here, can you see Milverse with a green color?
Paul: It is the news. Last time I deleted everything. Okay, I did everything from scratch so that you guys can understand.
Paul: SK, can we do it with Docker Desktop?
Paul: I'm showing you Docker desktop only, no, right now.
Paul: I have this script, so directly in Docker Desktop? I don't think.
Paul: Because, that's why I've shared the script. In Docker Desktop, you can look into that part. So, image is available, and container is running. And can you see the port?
Paul: 19530 is basically the port for Milpus.
Paul: Everybody, please do the setup, I don't think it should take a very long time, I just showed you from scratch.
Paul: For how many of you it is done?
Paul: More than 10 people in the chat has told it's done. What about others? Quickly, let me know.
Paul: Windows users, I think it might take a little bit of time.
Paul: Just be sure in admin mode, pulling, okay, pull, complete, done already, just check, okay. Otherwise, here also, you can check simply do a docker ps.
Paul: hyphen, you will see that Milverse is running. If you are not opening Docker Desktop, it's fine, but just be sure that you can do a confirmation from the terminal.
Paul: Doing it via program, taking time. Alright, fine.
Paul: But, the core thing is, going forward, please remember the…
Paul: This particular port where it is running. For Millverse, it is 19,530. Okay, so sometimes you might forget it, and if you really, look into, there is another with 9091.
Paul: I think this part with respect to… let me just show you that part also.
Paul: I think…
Paul: With respect to running mildews.
Paul: You can see the Milvers data volume will be mapped, so that's why I deleted everything. This YML file will also come into the picture.
Paul: Docker, Linux… Okay, and this is a web UI that you have?
Paul: Can you see here the web UI?
Paul: the Milverse is running successfully in my system. So, just do a little bit of strolling from here. So, right now, I don't have any collection, guys. So, for sure, it's a blank one, but this is exactly how your cluster looks like.
Paul: Okay, if anybody wants to access it, please go through the documentation, everything is written in this part. So just check everything is opening or not. People who have done the installation, just check the Milverse web UI is opening or not. Please have a check.
Paul: How many of you can see this one?
Paul: Working, Rajat, great.
Paul: 880MB downloaded. 880mb, yes, I think, it will take, the sizes towards the bigger site.
Paul: It's a one-time setup, going forward, it will be easier. Okay, working and could check in localhost, yes, please do have a check.
Paul: Local host, also, you can write. Replace that 127.001, you can write localhost. I have no issues in there.
Paul: Download in progress, alright, Santosh, working fine. Take 2-3 minutes, I think, in your system, it should be done.
Paul: Now, this is an invoice, so directly, I feel that going forward, we will be using Mailverse a lot, so at least let's do the setup here.
Paul: Alright, once you guys are done, let me know.
Paul: Okay, everybody, getting an error, please check, because here, nothing I can do.
Paul: whoever is getting error, because, see, I am just following the documentation, and whatever is written in the documentation, that only I have done. I've done nothing fancy.
Paul: According to your operating system, just pick up which one that you need.
Paul: Because you have something like web port block in your office laptop and other things, that can be some issue. Really, I have no idea in that case.
Paul: anybody who's in Windows, if you really want to share your screen and show me anybody. Because I know for Mac and Linux, it's…
Paul: Easy. Yes, people on Mac, and I think Mac and others.
Paul: Mac and Linux, I think there should not be any problem. Windows? For how many of you in Windows it's working, let me know in the chat quickly. Then I can actually ask.
Paul: In Mac, there should not be any problem only.
Paul: When Mac is direct.
Paul: If the port is blocked somehow in Mac also, it's not written to work.
Paul: Abhisheikh already. Abhis Sheikh, just then raise your hand, no. It will be easier if you can show to others also.
Paul: Imran, Abhishek, anybody who can share their screen with a good internet connection, please just show to others how you have done the setup, it will be a reference. Because this is the first time people with not enough, I can say, Docker, so…
Paul: I will just stop sharing mine. Okay, anyone like Abhishek, Imran, Abhishek is there. Abhishek, I am adding, okay?
Paul: Two panelists. Imran is also there. If some issue is there, Imran, then I'll be asking.
Paul: Okay?
Paul: I could not download the file, okay, fine.
Paul: Abhishek starts sharing, okay?
Paul: Simply show others. Step by step, what is the exact thing that you have done? Just…
Paul: Alright. Alright, Murthaza, this you have given directly… Alright, this I've not really tested it out.
Paul: From where you got this entire one?
Paul: This is a standalone version, I think.
Paul: Hmm?
Paul: Is it in documentation?
Paul: Because for you, it's fine, but for others, really…
Abhishek: Hi. Hi, hi, Paul. Yeah.
Paul: Yes, please, share from scratch.
Abhishek: Yeah, so I just went into the particular folder and, did this call command, right?
Paul: just,
Paul: Everybody just goes slow, okay? Because few people might be new, just show in the documentation exactly, that part.
Abhishek: So, if you go to the documentation…
Abhishek: Right, yeah, so there is… Just doing it.
Abhishek: Where is this called? Come on, yeah.
Abhishek: So, this convert?
Paul: Already, you have used WSL.
Abhishek: No, no, sorry, I have used Windows.
Paul: Then it will be a bad script, no?
Abhishek: Yeah, so that batch script, I, you know, installed it with the skull command.
Paul: Great, fine.
Paul: Alright, fine. Using CULD directly, you downloaded it.
Abhishek: Downloaded, yeah. So I downloaded this script, and then I executed this script, standalone bad.start, right? And I have already opened, the Docker desktop with administrator. So now it is showing, this Milwin standalone.
Paul: Pooh, Vendiram, could you, please post the… just paste that command in the chat?
Paul: And when you are, just paste that, people might need the reference. It's… you have to just use the keyword curl. That is the main thing. With hyphen L, it will be done.
Paul: Open your chat, I think we'll be having access.
Paul: And when you are pasting, just make sure it's for everyone.
Paul: Not only for me.
Paul: Okay, you don't have that access. Alright, fine, I will paste it, Abhishek.
Abhishek: Yeah, so this call command, it downloaded the standalone.bat, and I just executed this.
Abhishek: Standalone port bad start.
Abhishek: On the same folder, which… Oh, yeah.
Paul: You have to be in the same folder for sure, where the script is available, that is.
Paul: Alright guys, so pretty much two things.
Paul: Okay.
Abhishek: For that, the Docker should be up and running with administrator permission, yeah.
Paul: Okay, yeah, just open your Docker desktop with an admin privilege.
Paul: Okay, it's easy only then, because in Windows, I have not tested, that's why.
Paul: Alright, thanks, Abhishek.
Paul: She has used CMD only, no? I think she was using CMD.
Abhishek: Yeah, I was using CMT only.
Paul: Abhijit. Okay, any others, please quickly ask the question in the chat, he is there any…
Paul: No, I have a problem.
Paul: Because at least do the setup and just be sure it's here.
Paul: Okay, Git Bash is fine, I have no issues. Git Bash, anything in that, if you have WSL, use WSL. The main thing is the web UI. At least the health should be fine, if the web is also not working, because really… because I think it should work. You can see this web UI.
Paul: Alicia, web UI not working.
Paul: Alrighty, just check,
Paul: that, MS, in your case, that, image is running, no, fine. If the image will run, okay, so I will just stop sharing this part. Okay, I will start sharing the screen.
Paul: So this is the desktop 2.
Paul: This one, okay. Now, once after this, when you execute this cell, if the UI is not working, then also it is fine.
Paul: Okay? Not an issue. But just be sure your health check, it means that this should be working fine, guys.
Paul: It means that this should be executed.
Paul: Everybody please check, because this is a cell where we actually make a connection.
Paul: Excellent.
Paul: Yes, hyphen N for Windows, or otherwise… SFL is also fine.
Paul: For Windows-only heat is set.
Paul: That cell worked, okay, alright, fine. If that cell is working, fine.
Paul: I am just, the main thing is that cells should be working. UI, if it is not working, that is also fine. UI is not my priority right now.
Paul: Alright, from PyMailverse, import connection, you have added that import. After that, it worked fine, like, in whichever way.
Paul: Because file mode, connections, if you really look into in the top part only, I have taken that import, so I thought it should work. Banupia, yes?
Paul: Please have a check, because then…
Paul: The part is small only, today we can complete, but at least Milver should be up and working in your system then only.
Paul: For how many of you this cell is working, please let me know in the chat with a yes.
Paul: Everybody?
Paul: With a yes.
Paul: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10. What about others?
Paul: What about others? Please let me know.
Paul: For how many of you, it's not working?
Paul: Okay, web UI fail doesn't matter, Ashok.
Paul: The cell should be working. It doesn't matter to me the way we work. The WebVY really doesn't matter.
Paul: Okay, for how many of you, it's not working? Please write with the no, no, no, no.
Paul: Okay, nobody aside.
Paul: Okay, few people not working. Alright, fine. I'll be looking into the issues. Okay, so… let's focus on that part, okay? So, don't worry, I'll be looking into that when I'll be taking the route, so you can show me.
Paul: Alright, so, exactly what we have done in the cell, let's try to understand. First of all, I'm trying to make a connection.
Paul: Okay, so right now, the default, alias name, as you can see, these are the default settings for Milbus. I have not changed anything, any configuration right now. If any custom configuration that needs to be added, there is a user.yml file. So right now, I don't need that. I'm using the default one.
Paul: So, connected to Millverse, that you will be getting. Now, we have to define a collection schema. It means that whenever you are working in Milverse, Milverse, and similarly, if I fail,
Paul: In other places, you really don't need to define a schema, but
Paul: Creating a collection schema is very, very important, so that's why I feel that, like, Quadrant and, these, Quadrant, Melvos, these type of vector databases are much better at any point of time. Nitesh, great, it's working for you.
Paul: Bhanupriyat.
Paul: Yes, I will come to your question, don't worry, when I'll be taking the doubts.
Paul: So, here I am defining. So, like, as you see here, the PK. PK stands for primary key, basically. Okay, then what type of data type that you will be having?
Paul: Okay, so string type is primary is equal to true, auto ID, auto-generate the ID, so, well, I can see that you will be looking into multiple chunks in their unique IDs for each document that will be generated.
Paul: Max length, for Varka that I've defined is 100.
Paul: Okay, now this is for primary key definition, then comes your text field definition.
Paul: Okay? Then comes your BM25 sparse vector field definition, and your split.
Paul: And if you really look into both the schema or theme, only the name is different, one place BM25 vector, that I have given in the schema, and here's plate vector. And really, both of them are… both of them will be having followed values.
Paul: Okay, now, this is… can be, I can say, a somewhat new way of building and collection, but I feel this is always a safer approach. You should always have a schema.
Paul: Without a schema, even for your databases, you guys, first of all, decide what type of schema there it will be, then only you start, so the… yes?
Paul: for every database, whether you are working with Postgres or anything.
Paul: So, that's a very similar approach, so I feel that this is good.
Paul: Alright, now, fine. So, this is the part with respect to this one. So, I have just defined the schema. In the next case one, the schema is defined. So, creating the schema, the collection schema, and I am passing all the fields one by one.
Paul: So, within… to define a collection schema, you need the field scheme. Field schema, you can think about child, and the collection schema is the main parent.
Paul: Okay, right now, metadata doesn't… metadata doesn't matter right now, my mouth. Okay?
Paul: Perfect.
Paul: Because both are sparse embeddings. For sparse embeddings, you really, like, it is not always necessary. Generally, metadata, we keep it in dense level, ma'am, okay? Not in sparse level. Right now, I'm talking in sparse level, not in dense level.
Paul: Alright, now, in the next step, I will be creating a collection, so I've given, simply given a name here, so BM25 split, so now the collection definition, and here I am passing the schema.
Paul: Okay, and the collection will be created.
Paul: Now, here, for the sparse index that I have, so two things, the metric, one is IP, which is referred to as the inner product similarity. Now, generally for sparse indexes that we do. And now, this inner product, it is not necessary in every vector database, the name is same.
Paul: Okay? So sometimes only it's referred to as product also.
Paul: And, what type of index? So, sparse inverted index. So, the core index type for saving these sparse vectors.
Paul: Now, once I have defined what type of sparse, now in the next step, create the index. Now, this is the place where your indexes will be created.
Paul: So, multi-level index creation, if you really look into it.
Paul: So, this I have already done.
Paul: I think… Alright.
Paul: Please let me know for this part.
Paul: Okay, Satish, great, if Melbours is working.
Paul: Alright.
Paul: Now, we have just created the index and nothing more.
Paul: Collection is created, index is created.
Paul: In the next step, we need to feed the data. So here, I have taken a simple approach. I have used here NumPy. Okay, so NumPy, yes, NLTK error. Okay, Nitesh, please install NLTK. Then you won't be getting that error.
Paul: People are, yes, I think. If you are getting certification verifying, failed, it means some type of internet issue. Please have a check on that.
Paul: All right. Now, this is the part where you are actually doing a sparse to dictate means that I'm changing that data type. So, exactly the return type, how it will look. The index and value.
Paul: Okay, now this is the format. So sometimes, I felt that in the newer version, actually, like, I tested it in the older version, it was working fine, but in the newer version, I was getting an error. So, I've actually done this particular conversion using SKLearn.
Paul: pure SQL-based approach.
Paul: Okay?
Paul: Now, in, directly in SKLN, you have this particular modeling through which you can actually convert this sparse matrix into a ticked format. Through that, I have defined this.
Paul: Now, previously, this was not required, really. You can directly, pass the definition. So, once the definition was done, you can directly pass it, but this time, as it was not working, so I've done a workaround, as simple as that.
Paul: So, simply converting the embeddings into Milverse format. So, Milverse actually…
Paul: take the input into the format of a dictionary index value. So, this is the value through… now, this value is not similar for quadrant. This value can be different. So, always remember that. Millverse follows this rule, so it's not necessary that Quadrant will do, or VV8 will do.
Paul: Now, once I have done the conversion of my original data in the Milverse format, now in the next step, I'll be performing, basically, for the conversion format through this function. Sparse to date, you will see that I'll be taking the sparse to date VEC for every BM25, and similarly for Splat.
Paul: And then, this is the main definition. In the next step, I'll be performing the…
Paul: Insert operation. So generally, insert or upsert, operation, the idea is to push the data into the vector databases.
Paul: Okay, so once this vector data message that I have pushed.
Paul: Okay, I know that, through the UI, I can do a verification, actually. So, if I go to collections.
Paul: Can you see here? BM25? Sometimes this EY is low, it takes time, but you will be getting that, yes.
Paul: Okay, so the different type, what is the schema, the partition, all this information that you'll be getting from here.
Paul: Okay, so I know that, yes, it has been created. Please have a check, everybody. I think for everybody, this cell should be working.
Paul: This is… because, really, like, in other databases, it's really easy, but in Milverse, this is the correct approach. First, define field schema.
Paul: Through field schema, you'll be defining the collection schema, then you have to be sure that the data that you are working with, it is in Milverse format. Okay, then only you can perform an insert or an absurd operation.
Paul: Anko shares working and reflect on the UI side. It will reflect, don't worry.
Paul: All right.
Paul: I think, I've just changed the name.
Paul: Now, once… so I can say the data is pushed. Now I can perform anything. So, first of all, let's load the collection. So…
Paul: That's why, where it is running, I've defined that.
Paul: Now, on top of this, I'll be performing multiple operations. So, perform search, you can see.
Paul: Now, here, in this particular method, both. If method is equal to, like, BM25, or method. So, directly through a parameter, I can change this. As you can see.
Paul: This is just a parameter for this particular function, and here, I'm limiting the result to 3, the query type.
Paul: Okay, and one mode that I have taken is hybrid. So, hybrid is directly available, okay, it means that you can actually compare both the methods. So, a detailed approach that I have taken. Now, this hybrid here.
Paul: I have taken these two requests, guys.
Paul: Okay, so don't think about any, like, dense vector data taken into account.
Paul: Okay.
Paul: No?
Paul: The first one…
Paul: If method is equal to BM25, okay, encoding the queries. Okay, so basically, I'll be passing some queries. The idea is to encode them. Client.search, I'm telling that within which collection you will be doing that. Now, once the query is there, you need to convert them into that same format, so that's why sparse to dict
Paul: ANN field, so BM25 vector, now this is the actual field on top of which I want to perform my search. If you remember, in my field schema, I have defined this.
Paul: Okay? So, your field schema, if you remember, this is where I have defined. Similarly, for your split vector.
Paul: So, on both of these fields, I'll be applying.
Paul: So, it becomes much more optimized rather than doing it on that entire thing.
Paul: So here, similarly, so in the output field, we'll be looking into the major leak text. Similarly here, same definition.
Paul: That we do have. But here, the field that we'll be looking into, so the collection, if you really look into, the collection is the same, but within that collection, you have multiple fields. So, on top of multiple fields, I am actually doing a search.
Paul: Now, this part, if you really look into now, this is a hybrid one, where I have taken BM25 with Splate. Okay, so two different requests that I am doing, an NNN search request, so on top of the BM25, okay, as well as on the split vector.
Paul: Okay, and here I have given the output type. So, IP range, so inner product, inner product has a range between 0 to infinity. So, higher the value, it is always better.
Paul: Okay, now, finally, these two request one and request 2 through a hybrid RRF, I will try to combine both the results. Now, RRF can be used to combine your dense plus sparse, as well as, like, BM25, with the other approach. So, now, this approach, simply, I have taken into account.
Paul: Okay, and let me show you the results.
Paul: Okay, so, output schema, BM25, okay, I think, somewhere, that, name issue is there.
Paul: Just wait.
Paul: Somewhere in which line it was there.
Paul: schema not ready. I don't think there should be a problem with the schema.
Paul: I think with an extra collection.
Paul: Just wait, just wait. If I have done the initialization, That, because the name matters… Collection…
Paul: Okay, collection with an O is fine, because somewhere I feel that this demo spelling, I have made a mistake.
Paul: I was actually creating multiple indexes that time, so this is fine, VM25, SPLAT demo, there is no issue here.
Paul: Okay, collection.load perform search.
Paul: This is 25 split demo.
Paul: This is 25… there is 00 in demo.
Paul: No, no, no, in your case, there can be double O. In my case, I've just now created with a single O. Okay. That, there is no issue in that.
Paul: But somewhere I feel that I might have, missed that.
Paul: So, just wait, let me check, compare all the methods… Bm25 splash… Okay, alright, query method.
Paul: Such.
Paul: Method is equal to… this is the default initialization.
Paul: But, really, like, I feel that there should not be any problem.
Paul: Because the schema already…
Paul: Alright, name type, oh, alright, fine, I will just create a new one, it doesn't matter to me, let me just create a new one.
Paul: But I know in other places, I have actually changed that.
Paul: So, created collection, this one, VM running 5. Okay, let me just create a new collection right now.
Paul: standard embedding code.
Paul: Alright, now, just wait, let me do a verification from collections.
Paul: Okay, demo.
Paul: They sometimes take time to load, as you can see.
Paul: Alright, with a double load that I have done, based on the same schema only, alright.
Paul: Now, BM25 split demo. Alright, here, let me add a O.
Paul: In other places also, I need to update collection name, demo, here also, one who is required.
Paul: Here, also, one O is required.
Paul: Okay, so let me just check any other places that I need to update.
Paul: I don't think there are any other places, so let me check whether it works or not.
Paul: Just because of one note, it was creating the issue.
Paul: Alright, now the collection loaded and ready for search.
Paul: Okay, it is in create collection. Probably, that's why I was getting an error, it's fine. But, right now, I can see the collection loaded, and we can perform such operation.
Paul: Now, simply, like, semantic quotient with Synonium variations, as this is my first query that I am passing.
Paul: So, let's try to do… so here, as you can see, compare all methods, okay? And, query one that I'll be passing, and for everything, I'll be passing the limit.
Paul: Okay? So, just try to analyze the result. The output that you are getting, it's based on IP, okay? An inner product. That happens. So, if you really look into the scores, higher scores are always better. BM25, what is the score that you are getting?
Paul: Guys, BM25, what is the score? Can I say 8.4, 8.43, based on… and really, like, I feel that these two documents are pretty much the same. Not a lot of difference. But here, can you see at least
Paul: Okay, now, SPLAT neural that I have written, because generally, once we are talking with respect to SPLAT, we refer them as
Paul: sparse neural vectors, okay?
Paul: Because, actually, it uses a neural network.
Paul: So here, can you see the improvement with respect to the scores? You are getting higher scores, at least, in both of the cases that I can see.
Paul: Okay, and I feel, in my case, the same documentary indexing that might have happened because of that. Please have a check, I think for everybody, Splat should have higher values.
Paul: please let me know in the chat, because I think only this is the part. Hybrid RRF also didn't work in this case, because really there is no dense that I have taken. I've just created a hybrid of BM25 with
Paul: split. So, this is not actual hybrid.
Paul: Guys, please let me know, is split working the best?
Paul: In the chat. Everybody, please let me know.
Paul: for every one of your splats should work. Ravi told years, Ankosh is telling, yes, working. The idea was to prove to you, okay, because of that, I have taken that into account.
Paul: Alright, fine.
Paul: Alright, so majorly, so this part is done. Tomorrow, I think we will be talking with respect to RRF and a few other things, because now this RRF is a little bit different. So, this is not pure hybrid search, this is not a mixture. This is actually a mixture of sparse
Paul: plus sparse. Not sparse plus dense. I hope everybody understands this part.
Paul: Slade will have the highest proportion.
Paul: Now, one thing you can do… okay, so… let's try to do that also.
Paul: If you remember, in our,
Paul: definition, so this part. Please change the model and update the model. Everyone.
Paul: Here, okay? I will be picking up the best one.
Paul: So, this is the best one, let me just copy the name.
Paul: And let me paste it. I will just check that whether I'm getting higher scores or not, that is the main agenda. Now, this Splat is the latest model that I am using. Previously, it was Splat V1, the core V1 version.
Paul: Okay? But right now, I am using the latest one, and you have to just re-execute all the sales, that's the only requirement.
Paul: Okay, so I think from here…
Paul: let me… even for my case, this will be downloading for the first time.
Paul: some hugging phase. Okay, access to Splat is restricted. You need to actually get a model access for this one. Okay, I actually, I didn't…
Paul: Do a sign-up, so I think,
Paul: Login, let me just do a login.
Paul: Okay, now, once you have the access to the model, okay, then you can actually get it.
Paul: But again, I feel that I need the API key, otherwise it cannot do the verification for this.
Paul: Just wait.
Paul: Everybody, please, create your own, because today's class is done, the idea was to test it with the main model.
Paul: Okay, yes.
Paul: Alright, fine, today's class is done, whoever wants to drop, they can drop. Please, people do have a testing with the new version of Splat.
Paul: Okay, other US guys, you guys can drop. Okay, please let me know. Do the setup tutorial and let me know that, what is the improvement that you were getting when you were working with Splate V3.
Paul: The model name is this one. But you need to model access, everybody. From Hugging Face, you need to get the access.
Paul: And through an API, you have to do the validation also.
Paul: Because this is the default one, K tokens, key…
Paul: Otherwise, we can manually downloading it to Hugging Face, okay? That is the other way around, but this is a task that I'm giving you, just, do it, okay? Please test out. There are, multiple versions of Splat.
Paul: I think I have kept it in the notes, okay? So…
Paul: Can you see here? Upgrade to Navrsplat P3? I think this will work really good. There is another V22 Maxis also there.
Paul: Aww.
Paul: Okay, I think that particular model, I have not kept it, but, right now, this is the 2024 paper, which the Splat came, so please do the testing with SPLAT V3, and then let me know tomorrow, like, what is the result that you are getting. I think everybody can do that.
Paul: Muchaser will need to run this? Alright, okay, take your time.
Paul: Other notebooks also I have shared, so just go through them also, if you need to do the setup.
Paul: All right, fine. I think we are done for today. Tomorrow, we'll be talking about RRF.
Paul: That, hybrid search.
Paul: Okay, and then finally with our revamping.
Paul: All right, now, people with questions, they can start. Okay, Vanu, let's take your questions on what you were asking.
Paul: Yes, Vanu, Kiran, Deva.
Bhanu Priya: Hi, Paul. Am I audible?
Paul: Yes, you want.
Bhanu Priya: Yeah, Paul, I actually joined, very late, and I completed all the recordings, and started with the project one, okay? And, the thing I tried with, embeddings, Hugging Face embeddings, and Grok API, okay? So it was… it worked for Notebook Level 1 and all, but when I did in the Project 1, right, Project 1, there, I found, like.
Bhanu Priya: which you highlighted the error, like, error, I was getting error. It was like, I'm getting… I used 384, but the dense vector choosed some 1536 and all, like that. How much ever I hard-coded in all the places, still I'm facing the error.
Bhanu Priya: So, is it, like, only open API I need to go through, or how it is.
Paul: Can you share the screen and show me quickly?
Bhanu Priya: Okay, yeah, sure, one minute.
Paul: Because I think, if it is defined in the config file.linuv file, these two are the main sources.
Paul: Correct.
Bhanu Priya: Dimension, yeah, embeddings, dimension, and I tried to…
Bhanu Priya: One minute. I, I actually just took the screenshot.
Paul: I'm not finding the share option. Okay, I will add you to panelists, then only will get it.
Bhanu Priya: Okay.
Bhanu Priya: And I'll recreate, some options and all, like, they have given. I tried all, but still…
Paul: Show me, show me, because really, like, sometimes…
Bhanu Priya: still. Yeah, I got it, yeah. Sorry.
Paul: it, no.
Paul: They were selling Malcos as a framework that has.
Bhanu Priya: Yeah, yeah, I got it.
Paul: Where it helped to run this one.
Paul: I need to check, I have not gone through Malvis yet.
Bhanu Priya: see, this one, it is, like, existing quadrant collection is configured for dense vector 1536, but I didn't give… I gave, like, embedded, dimensions in the config file where you gave, right? There, I hard-coded in the… even in the code also, embeddings.ip and BY, there also I've given 384, but still, I was… I was stuck with this other.
Bhanu Priya: Set force, recreate parameter true.
Paul: I got it, because it's telling you to recreate the collection for that part, but 384 should be overwritten. If you have changed, just check your config file.env file, those files, everywhere if you have done 384, because that comes as a source.
Paul: That's fine.
Bhanu Priya: Yeah, I have given, actually, and I have given the delete connect… delete collection, and then, again, create also. That also, I tried recreate. That also didn't work. Maybe for our course purpose, I should go through open API…
Paul: It doesn't matter which embedding model. The first thing I told, use any model, just be sure you are handling the dimension. That is the main thing.
Paul: So, in my code, I feel that in the project one. Somewhere in the config file, have you updated it? If you have updated.
Bhanu Priya: Yes.
Paul: the dot TNV, then it should work. That's the main thing.
Bhanu Priya: Okay, sure, I'll retry. And one more question I have, to the entire course, how much it may charge if I take OpenAI key?
Bhanu Priya: P.
Paul: Something at the minimum, $2 or $5 recharge.
Paul: I have done…
Bhanu Priya: Sit down?
Paul: now, in this course, I have, as an instructor, I have taken a $10.
Paul: Till now, my $10 is not exhausted. I know that after 3 months also, it only be exhausted.
Bhanu Priya: Okay, then for us, 5 is enough, right?
Paul: Yes, yes.
Bhanu Priya: Okay, okay, thank you, thank you so much. I'll retry once again.
Paul: Yes, so…
deba: Alright… Next, Karen.
Kiran Rathod: Sorry.
deba: Well, I was facing that issue for installation. I can say that it has got resolved.
Paul: Alright, goodly.
deba: Dick Vijer…
deba: Yes, Deva, first you go. Yeah, hi. So I have two questions. Actually, the last part, I probably could not get much, so the thing is, which part? The Milverse part, that is a vector database you installed, right? Or you deployed in the Docker container, no? Nothing, nothing. See, I have just taken a Docker instance. In that Docker instance, the Milverse is running.
deba: That's the only thing.
deba: Okay. And the model that you have is BM25, or any other model, for that, Milverse is no way linked, actually, it is just for the… Nothing linked, nothing linked. Okay, that, that, that I got confused. See, BM25, I have taken that BM25 implementation from, Milverse, Pi Milwa's.
deba: model. So there, there is a direct function, through which I know the formula will be called, and the vectors will be created. But for Splat, you need a model. Okay, that's why there, in the next step, I defined the Hugging Face. In both the cases, I've just created the sparse.
deba: vectors. Now, there was some compatibility, like, compatibility issues when I was pushing. So, what I've done, I've manually converted them into that dict value format.
deba: Which Milverse takes it for upsetting, any upset operation. That is the only thing that I have done.
deba: After that, I've just done a comparison operation.
deba: Okay, and Hugging Face model that you downloaded, primarily, right, for running this? Yes, yes, the default one, which is written, that one. And later on, I told, please do have a check with the Splate V3, that is much better. Everybody tells that, you get…
deba: like, a better, at least 10% to 15%, much higher quality sparse embedded. And that is also available in Hugging Face, the split between? Yes, yes, yes, yes, it is available, but you need that access.
deba: Okay, okay, I mean, I might be… Yeah, sex is free, or to just click on it.
deba: Okay, okay, yeah, sure. And one more question. It is slightly with the older context, actually. So, I'm currently doing some kind of chunking and embedding on top of a massive JSON data. What I find is the metadata going beyond
deba: 8,000 bytes, actually. So, is it really recommended to have such long metadata? And I'm processing more than 500 files. For each JSON file, the metadata goes more than 8,000 bytes. So, do you recommend to have that way? Do I need to put it in some hierarchical manner?
deba: Or do I need to use the call bart, or something like that for managing those? Because… just I need some of your, you know, idea. 8,000, really? I don't work with 8,000. 8,000, even I cannot remember. Like, now you have to really filter it out.
deba: Which one you feel? You can create a hierarchy level, for example, you created 5 hierarchies, under those 5 hierarchies, it made 400, 400, and then also 8000 is really high.
deba: Very high. Okay, like, 8,000 is really high. I have… maximum goal, like, 200, 300, that is fine.
deba: Because with that, also, a cost will come. 8,000 is really high. So that means I have to remove certain parameters out of this metadata, right? A few things I have to… Yes, just think that which is irrelevant. Yeah. Which is not making sense, or basically, you have to think from during prediction.
deba: How that metadata will help you, think about that. And the parameters which are actually not helpful, remove them simply.
deba: Thank you so much, yeah, got it, got it.
deba: Alright.
Paul: Yes, Dig Vijay, Mantage, Viraj.
digvijay reddy: So, Paul, I have a question. The… let's say…
digvijay reddy: Milbus, right, if we have 6,000 page document, right, like, if in interview they ask which, database have you used, so can we tell, can this functionality be available in Pinecall or Vivate as well?
Paul: I can say Pinecon, lesser functionalities, Melvos, Quadrant, they are much better.
Paul: Okay, now it totally depends upon seeing. Right now, in the market, for scalability, as they market their product.
Paul: Zealous is one that is based on Milpus.
Paul: Okay, so generally, if I'm consulting my clients, I generally say, try to go with Quadrant, Milverse, 3 options. Now, out of that, whatever that budget comes out, that is their decision.
digvijay reddy: Okay.
Paul: not to worry, but I feel that, Quadrant and Millville, they are really, really powerful.
Paul: We view it also.
digvijay reddy: Okay.
digvijay reddy: Okay, yeah, that's horrible from my side.
Paul: Okay, but, it totally is. So, let's see, when you are suggesting even, like, because most of my clients, they say that my data is already on MongoDB, so do the work on Mongo.
digvijay reddy: Yeah, that'.
Paul: In Mongo, there are limitations. Similarly, like, people with Postgres, they come to me, then that's the other thing. But certain level of optimization, that cannot be done.
Paul: But how about the day value?
Paul: How?
digvijay reddy: What about the data privacy and security, if we go for other…
Paul: You can host it in your own.
Paul: There are options, they also use their cloud. Otherwise, you host it in your own infra. Long term, it will be cheaper. See, always do a calculation. It means that when you are telling your client, you have to get that, okay, for 1 billion vectors, this is the cost that is coming.
Paul: Now, just think about you, I'm telling 1 billion, just think, if you bring
Paul: If you do an hybrid approach, then it will automatically become 2 billion.
digvijay reddy: Yeah.
Paul: Okay, because the same for every, chunk, you'll be saving that sparse as well as dense. Automatically, the charge will become home. Now, the question comes, for your, dense, you know that the dimensions will be 1536.
Paul: Okay.
digvijay reddy: now comes…
Paul: that the dimension, because they charge you on each level. Number of vectors comes dimension also. In sparse, if you take a dimension of 30,000 that I told you to display.
Paul: Again, your costs will increase.
Paul: So, you have to think from every perspective.
Paul: Okay, like, how? Tomorrow, a little bit, I'll be talking about this one with respect to pricing. Generally, for senior level only, it is important. Junior level, guys, you really don't need to do, but I feel that, yes, that cost estimation that you have to always do, at least from one year to two-year perspective.
digvijay reddy: Yeah. And one more request, Paul. Like, in the second project, right? Like, can we pick up a document which is… which is having at least a thousand pages? Like, 1,000 to 2,000 pages, and to retrieve… I mean, perform these sort of operations on that?
Paul: Really, the size of the document doesn't matter.
Paul: Okay. I can pick up a 1,000-page document. As you told, the cost of embedding, only comes to an higher site. So, really, like.
Paul: If you remember one task that I've given, probably that particular PDF I will pick up, it was close to 300 pages.
Paul: 1000, 2000, I can do it, but again, because for now, I'll be using every free thing. Okay, probably if I'm going with, I think, in your next part, it is quadrant, or I don't remember your second project that I've configured.
Paul: There, you have your SQL also. For SQL, I need to build some dummy data that I will be doing this week. But, see, 1000, 2000 will be high. If you can provide me a PDF 1000, okay, it has to be some type of book that you will be doing.
Paul: Okay, really, we can't verify the data also, at least to a certain extent. I can pass it, because at the end of the day, it is just that document passing in that. If we want, we can.
digvijay reddy: No, like, I got a use case where we have a 6,000-page document chunk, okay? Like, we need to get the data out of it, like, it has SQL, like, Tableau format in Excel as, right? Tableau data as well. Like, how do we correctly.
Paul: Right now, I'm… I won't be talking about multimodal, that particular format exactly, that part, I will come when that will be your fourth project. There, I'll be talking about images, tables, those things, much more. Because there, I'll be using GPU very specifically.
Paul: CPU things they cannot do to that particular extent.
Paul: Through image level also, to a certain extent, docklings can handle, but not through that.
digvijay reddy: But we have to do parsing, right? We need to…
Paul: is passing, you will be doing. Just, I'll be changing the liability. If you want, I'm just telling you, just go through this.
digvijay reddy: Okay.
Paul: See, Use this one.
Paul: You're good.
digvijay reddy: Okay.
Paul: So generally, through this, I actually convert my data. So you can see transform complex documents into, like, PDFs, markdown, multiple supports are there, but it really requires a GPU on top of a CPU, it performs very, very bad.
Paul: That's me.
Paul: And really, and if you look into the number of stars, 51.8K, so I hope you understand.
digvijay reddy: Yeah.
Paul: widely used.
digvijay reddy: Okay.
Paul: Just say, during your multi-data classes, I will be telling you this part.
Paul: But, not for now.
digvijay reddy: Okay. I mean, I gave a couple of interviews, the questions were like this, so, like, I…
digvijay reddy: That's the reason I just asked.
Paul: Alright, fine. You can test it out by yourself also. In interviews also, you can say.
Paul: Okay. Because if you really look into your DRAM, 6GB, 10GB, 8GB,
Paul: Okay, so that's why that VRAM requirement is there.
digvijay reddy: But does this work on MacBook Pro? I don't think so, right? Like…
Paul: No, in MacBook, which one you have, it totally depends. M1, M2, Pro versions, if you have, or a Mac version, it will work. You have MPS there, metal…
Paul: Okay, there it works. It has, you can see here, GPUs are Apple Silicon.
digvijay reddy: Yeah, yeah, correct, yeah.
digvijay reddy: Sure, thanks a lot, Paul, I'll go through this, yeah.
Mantaaj: Hey, Paul. Paul, quick question on this one, which Rick Vinay has asked, right, for the quadrants. So, when we are using it, are we using the quadrant?
Mantaaj: the licensed services from it, or we go through AWS and take the services for the storage and everything?
Paul: Thief.
Paul: when you do this one, let's take Quadrant. Quadrant is actually using behind-the-scenes AWS only. When you launch Quadrant, okay, so for example, if I go to this pricing section, okay, now this comes private cloud. You will be using your own cloud.
Paul: deploy Quadrant fully on-prem. It means that on your own Kubernetes cluster, they will actually help you out to do the entire setup. Complete data isolation.
Mantaaj: Okay.
Paul: Okay, now there is a hybrid cloud where multiple… generally, I don't prefer hybrid cloud so much, okay, and this is the managed cloud. It means that they have their own AWS, GCP, Azure infra on top of that loop.
Mantaaj: Oh, God.
Mantaaj: Right. So we generally go with the first managed cloud options only, right?
Paul: No, we go with this one, private.
Mantaaj: That would help.
Paul: This is for learning the.
Mantaaj: learning purpose.
Paul: Or very small, just think about if you have a very small amount of data, you feel that probably less than 10GB of data.
Paul: Then I will go with this one.
Mantaaj: This one.
Paul: Because, actually, what is the main problem? As I told you, this horizontal and vertical scaling. Now, this actually takes a lot of money, they take.
Paul: Which I feel that it can be cheaper if I use my own infra.
Paul: This is the only, place.
Paul: Because the rest of the features, high availability, auto-healing, everything comes with EKs, nothing you need to worry about.
Paul: And as they tell, zero downtime upgrades, but…
Paul: Like, zero tolerance down, but I believe AWS, GCP, everything is down, they will also be down.
Paul: Nothing that we can do.
Mantaaj: Okay, got it, got it. And, Paul, my other question is, is related to some… one of the POC that I'm trying to do in my organization. So, what we're trying to do is.
Mantaaj: We have a Swagger stuff, right, which is all… we have a data in the form of a JSON. So, what I'm trying to do is, from that JSON, reading that JSON, and I'm trying to convert those JSON into the BDD scenarios, okay? Reading it out.
Mantaaj: So,
Mantaaj: So just want to know, like, when I'm reading this JSON, should I convert those JSON into the embeddings, and then,
Paul: No, no, no, no, no. First of all, before embedding, just be sure. Embedding is always the last step. Any type of data manipulation and transformation that you have to do, it has to be before that.
Mantaaj: Okay.
Mantaaj: So… so should I parse it before it? Because I'm a little confused, how should I…
Paul: Just do the bathroom.
Mantaaj: Okay.
Paul: Okay, and make it in a format that is better, like, easier for Amy, I can say, because, through that, you'll be making chunks and other things, so that's where that chunks become somehow meaningful.
Mantaaj: Okay, okay, got it.
Mantaaj: Okay, got it. Thanks.
VRAJ PATEL: Hi, sir.
Paul: Alright, Viraj, yeah, Virajk home.
VRAJ PATEL: Sir, thank you so much for today's session. I have two questions. One is related to the today's session regarding the retrieval fusion.
VRAJ PATEL: Oh.
VRAJ PATEL: Fusion Retriever.
VRAJ PATEL: In which, why we are,
VRAJ PATEL: Do the similarity search and retrieve all the documents that we are stored in the vector store, rather than going to do the similarity search on… based on the user's query only.
Paul: this… Let's see, like, similarity search, why we are doing, on top of what?
VRAJ PATEL: In the vector store.similarity search, we are just…
Paul: If open the screen once, I think it will be better. Alright, we're talking about today's one. Let's go to Fusion Triple, yes.
Paul: Alright, yes, tell me now. Which part you are telling that we are doing.
VRAJ PATEL: The Fusion Retriever.
Paul: Okay, perfusion retrieval will come.
Paul: On, create VM25, yes, this part, yes, still.
VRAJ PATEL: Yes. In the step 1, vector store.similaritySert, in which we are passing the empty string, rather than passing the… what the user's query, right?
VRAJ PATEL: So why we are not finding the user's query here?
Paul: Okay, actually, it is based on the query only.
Paul: It means that right now, this is a placeholder.
VRAJ PATEL: Okay.
Paul: See, this particular document that I'll be taking into account, all docs on top of which we are performing.
Paul: Later on, I have defined this, my vector store, VM25, with this particular query.
VRAJ PATEL: Yes.
VRAJ PATEL: But we are not passing this query to the vector store.similarities as in that, and we are retrieving all the documents that we are storing in the vector store.
Paul: Because here, getting all the documents from Vector Store in the first step, because, just wait, let me just get the flow also, ones that I have told you in the class, because I feel initially we get…
Paul: all the documents from Victor Search.
Paul: Because the hypothetical embedding that needs to be generated… just wait, let me just look into that flow once, it will be clear.
Paul: No, I think somewhere around this one, this one. Yes, in this flow, get all the documents from the vector store, yes.
VRAJ PATEL: Okay.
Paul: On top of the query, if you will do it, okay, very specific amount of chunks only that you will be getting.
Paul: That's why we are not doing it.
Paul: And here, very specifically, if you look into the code, the value will be, like, index.inTotal, which refers, basically, it means that all the indexes, the total number of chums that you'll be getting.
VRAJ PATEL: Okay, okay.
VRAJ PATEL: Understood.
Paul: Okay, because, see, right now, for BM25 also, then you can say that very specifically, why we are not doing only searches from there.
Paul: We are performing a… actually, to generate that hypothetical embedding, we need the entire context.
Paul: Okay, now, if you are actually bringing the entire context in the paper, also, it has told that, yes, it will bring that noise into the picture. But, that noise really doesn't matter, okay, because with that noise, there will be some amount of hypothetical context.
Paul: Okay, so because of that, really, like, it won't create a very big issue.
VRAJ PATEL: Okay, understood, sir. And my second question is related to my recent project, where I am going to develop the
VRAJ PATEL: Platform that, guides users to how to do the debates right.
VRAJ PATEL: So, one of them, my client has the… some kind of materials related to the… how to do the debates and how should the debate style should be. And the second type of material is that in which they have the different, different topics related
VRAJ PATEL: debate materials, right? Like, geopolitics, public issues and availability.
VRAJ PATEL: now he wants to develop such a platform where the AI should guide the users based on the topic, to how to do the debates, and how the debate style should be. And it should be the
VRAJ PATEL: Related to the… that particular material. My question is that, if someone is, choose the topic, like, New World Order, right? So, we need to find the context from the geopolitics-related debates, and, second.
VRAJ PATEL: Kind of topics like,
VRAJ PATEL: I mean, second, context from the how to do the debates, and how does the debate style suit.
VRAJ PATEL: We'll be…
Paul: Alright, alright, I got your point.
VRAJ PATEL: Standard architecture should be there.
Paul: Alright, so a little bit about that. So, generally, like, if you want to break that conversation, like, the debate can be based on mathematics, the debate can be based on multiple things.
VRAJ PATEL: Okay. Now, generally, that information, during your chunking, you can keep it in metadata.
Paul: Okay, like, for each chunk, like, what type of metadata, and I really like that part. Later on, I'll be talking about this adaptive retrieval. Okay, so here, like, adaptive retrieval for distinct strategies tailored to different query types. Like, factual. In your case, the strategies can be different. Just have a go through this notebook, you will get it.
VRAJ PATEL: Okay, okay.
Paul: So, it means that here I've created multiple classes, basically. Like, fact class, analytical class, Opinion class, okay, context class, okay, and finally, if you look into the approach.
Paul: Okay, so, like, for every query classifier, I have a custom one, then based on that, I create, like, for this will be my… because here you can do much more optimized search, even based on metadata. I think that part, I have not taken it here.
VRAJ PATEL: Yay!
Paul: But it's the core retrieval part.
Paul: Because during your vector search, if you have this particular intent style, okay, now you can actually apply that filter before and only before the search. So it becomes, at least your search will be much more optimized.
VRAJ PATEL: Yes, I think I should create one retrieval engine also that, generate the query based on that topic also.
Paul: Yes, that's what you can do. From here, you can take reference, because I was thinking about discussing later, right? This is referred to as, like, a little bit adaptive retrieval side.
VRAJ PATEL: Gotcha.
Paul: Okay.
VRAJ PATEL: Thank you so much.
Paul: Alright.
Paul: I think no more questions for today. Nitesh? Nitesh?
Nitesh: Yeah, hi, brother.
Paul: Yes. Sorub is also there, is designed? Yes.
Nitesh: Well, let me share my screen, possibly, if I'll allow it, because I am not able to download the displayed model, actually. It's giving me an error that,
Nitesh: It's Spirit model.
Paul: E3.
Paul: which you are. For V2, you have to do an API-based verification, that's.
Nitesh: No, no, no, the first one, which is already.
Paul: First one only. It should, be default. Okay, show me that. Promote to panelist.
Nitesh: Sort of?
Paul: Thought of.
saurabh verma: Yeah, I want to share my screen.
Paul: Alright, so, share your screen from up to panelists, yes.
saurabh verma: So, Paul, I have shared my screen.
Paul: Yes, I can see.
saurabh verma: So, in this step.
Paul: Yes?
saurabh verma: That Milwass is required to be installed, huh?
saurabh verma: One minute.
Paul: Hmm.
saurabh verma: It was that step.
saurabh verma: Here, somewhere, yeah. So, if I show you my Docker, in that Milvas is installed.
saurabh verma: And on command prompt.
Paul: This is image. You have to show the container.
Paul: Container exited.
saurabh verma: container here.
Paul: Container not running, no?
saurabh verma: So, what should I do now? Run this, right?
Paul: Generally, you have to run that command that is given in the documentation.
Paul: start, embed that file. Like, I use Bash, and then the name of the file to start the service.
saurabh verma: You have given this at the top, that command also.
Paul: In the… from the documentation, you have to take that command.
saurabh verma: I came out of the Zoom, so I lost the history. If you can just paste that.
Paul: Open Chrome?
saurabh verma: Yeah, I've already opened Milwa's. I'm over here.
Paul: write Milverse installed docs.
saurabh verma: Milwa's…
Paul: Install docs.
Paul: Enter.
Paul: Run Mailverse in Docker Linux, click that.
Paul: Okay, now, according to your operating system, from the left-hand side, choose the option.
saurabh verma: Yeah, mine was Windows.
Paul: This one I take? Docker Desktop Windows?
Paul: Yes, if your system is Windows, then based on that, here, really not my choice.
saurabh verma: Right, so here then, run the downloaded script start.
Paul: Here you can see, like, standalone.pat start, that only you need to execute.
saurabh verma: So, I need to run as administrator and download the installation script. So, where I get the script? From here.
Paul: Yes, there it's written, no HTTPS, or you can use that call command also. Using call also, you can do a download.
saurabh verma: Okay.
saurabh verma: So, I go over here.
saurabh verma: Mr. Optical of the ministry.
saurabh verma: Why is she not running? She's not even gonna, mage failed.
Paul: Will selling not a correct path?
Paul: Or otherwise, just pass curl and rest of the HTTPS command.
saurabh verma: Yeah, I'm looking at that curl command also, someone had shared.
saurabh verma: Here, here, this one, huh?
Paul: Oh, this is this one.
Paul: That is actually a .sh file. Okay, so generally, if you have a WSL in your system, then it will work.
saurabh verma: Somewhere, someone had shown that.
Paul: Someone has shown, but he has written it manually.
saurabh verma: Oh, he had written manually. Actually, in Zoom, we can't copy, so I could not copy that command.
Paul: Just write it, no. It's only one word you have to write called space hyphen n.
saurabh verma: Okay, okay, where? Carl?
Paul: everything in small.
saurabh verma: Space, hyphen…
Paul: capital L, then paste that HTTP link, that entire
Paul: Till dot back. Not till last.
Paul: till last… no, no, not entire thing. That hyphen hyphen output file, that is not required. This one, dotbed. Paste it.
Paul: Yes, enter it.
saurabh verma: So, no.
Paul: Do an exit from here, just check the file is available or not.
Paul: Check the file is available or not.
saurabh verma: So it should be in their C users, right?
Paul: Hmm.
Paul: Because I'm sharing again the command that, I think Abhishek shared, just quit.
Paul: I think I will be having it in my history, from there you take it.
Paul: Okay, that… add that hyphen part also in the end, I think then only it will save the file. In Windows, it's different. I've shared it in the command, just take that.
Paul: you need that output file, otherwise I think it's just opening that file rather than saving it, so just be sure. In the chat, I have shared it.
saurabh verma: this I will take, you know?
saurabh verma: HTTPS… Now, this is something that I can copy.
saurabh verma: Okay, oh, now I got it.
saurabh verma: Okay, because it's yours.
saurabh verma: God, I need to write.
saurabh verma: Right?
Paul: In the meantime, let's take on with
Paul: You can also share some, Nitesh.
saurabh verma: Start sharing, don't wait. So now this is… this has come, so it is downloaded.
Paul: This file is available now in your system.
saurabh verma: So, it will be available in C user's user, right?
Paul: That's…
saurabh verma: will be standalone.bat. So, I have come to that folder, see users.
Paul: Generally, it's a good practice to do from the project directory.
Paul: Because, once you run the surface volume folder and other things.
saurabh verma: So from here, you mean to say, right? The terminal.
Paul: Yes, from this room, ma'am.
Paul: UCMD.
saurabh verma: What's this?
Paul: I already have shared that standalone. Okay, fine, this is a bad file, not a problem. So just copy-paste, no, again, why you were right there.
saurabh verma: that commander.
Paul: Yes, Saurabh, just copy-paste that. Already executed, then why again you were writing it?
Paul: Execute.
Paul: Now, run that command. Go back. I think that,
Paul: whatever is there to execute that script, I think start
Paul: That, go back to the documentation page.
Paul: Copy… documentation page, Milverse.
saurabh verma: Bye.
Paul: Windows, I think it won't be bash go above, go above.
Paul: Yes, below, check the command. Below, below, below, below, scroll down.
Paul: The standalone.bat start, right?
Paul: Yes, yes, Nitesh.
Paul: You fish?
Nitesh: Yeah, so I think I picked a couple of things. The only thing is that now this is getting errored out on… while downloading this, displayed, model, be… and it's asking… I mean, it's using the pip install torch.
Nitesh: And somehow, I don't have a pip, it says a pip 3. So I'm not sure how to change that command somewhere within these down labels.
Paul: Really? Generally, like, sometimes I create an alias pip3 is equal to pip.
Nitesh: Okay.
Paul: That's the only way I do it.
Paul: then automatically the system recognizes PayPal, BIP3, both are same.
saurabh verma: So, Paul, while this is coming up, I have one question.
saurabh verma: I'm working on one project.
saurabh verma: Just one minute.
saurabh verma: Jesus.
Amit Singh: Can I ask meanwhile, Pulsar?
saurabh verma: Yeah, yeah, please ask, then I'll…
Amit Singh: So, what sort of, like, I followed ChatGPT, it was not working for me in Windows, so I did it on WSL. I'm unable to start this, on .sh, that, it's not starting.
Paul: bash, and then the name of the script. Can I, can I share my screen? I mean, that's…
saurabh verma: I will stop sharing, yeah, you share.
Paul: No, no, fine, like, multiple people can share.
Amit Singh: Can you just add me to the list, yeah.
Paul: Yes, I'm glad.
Paul: Yes.
Paul: Take the correct command.
Paul: That file is available.
Paul: So, first of all, if you are inside the Milwa's directory, your directory is so much confused.
Paul: rag, then also again I can see rag. How many times it's there?
Amit Singh: You're trailing for me?
Paul: Yes.
Amit Singh: Oh, we need?
Paul: times in the left-hand side, I can see.
Paul: And while you are inside the Milbus folder, it has to be in the root only.
Paul: Maintain the project structure, please.
Paul: The way that I have shared it?
Amit Singh: I created this manually, you know, so…
Paul: No, manual creation is not required.
Amit Singh: I was following… this…
Paul: No.
Amit Singh: So if I come back… Hmm…
Paul: Just open your CMD, And just execute those two commands.
Paul: From this particular project directory, advanced rack tutorials folder. That is the bare minimum request, nothing else.
Amit Singh: And then, the fields… Sweet.
Paul: Right at the end, hyphen O.Part.
Paul: Please check the command that I have shared in the chat.
Amit Singh: No, Jessna, you mentioned that was not required, no?
Paul: No, no, no, add it, otherwise it's just showing you the content of the file, it is not getting saved, that's why.
Amit Singh: Yeah, earlier I had password.
Paul: Yes, execute this one.
Paul: In your system, call is not getting recognized.
Paul: Are you using CMD? I think in CMD it works.
Amit Singh: It did not happen, right?
Amit Singh: employee.
Paul: This screen could not resolve host.
Amit Singh: Would not at all hold standalone.batic.
Paul: Really, because… Hmm… Standalone, just then… because here, you can save the output file to any form, standalone underscore.
Paul: And veg.pat, that was the original name, then pass that original name only.
Paul: While generating the output file, you can pass any name.
Amit Singh: So our file name is, what, standalone or embed.bat only? I passed, no. Dash O. Dash O is for what?
Amit Singh: Standalone.
Paul: See, if you are not getting directly download the file from GitHub, that's the other way around.
Paul: why so much? If you're getting stuck, probably here, okay, because in the output file, I don't know why it is telling this one.
Paul: Could not resolve post standalone.vat, probably if the same file is there.
Paul: You are doing it in the Lenovo folder.
Paul: I told to do in the project folder. Just open that link and download the file, and keep it wherever you want. Do a copy-paste.
Paul: Done.
Paul: Open github.file and download that file.
Paul: that GitHub link, just directly download the file. If curl is not working, leave it.
Paul: Not my… that link, curl, that HTTPS link, open it and download it.
Amit Singh: Oh, that was… okay, okay.
Paul: That is the manual way.
Paul: If it is not working, do it that way.
Paul: We remove calls, just keep HD.
Amit Singh: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Paul: link, and remove that hyphen O and everything from the end.
Paul: Just download this file.
Paul: And save it in whichever. You can do a…
Amit Singh: So I delete the standalone.bat, right?
Paul: Delete that, no, you don't need that final output, it's only for CLI. Delete, delete, huh, now hit enter.
Paul: Okay, now save this flight. Done.
Paul: Manually save it. There is no such thing that you have to use. Why copy this? Why you have to copy? Click, click, save as.
Amit Singh: They don't look great.
Paul: Right-click, save as do it. What you were thinking so much?
Paul: Just give the name standalone.bat and save it in that particular folder.
Amit Singh: And save as type, remove text file to all files, I think. In Windows, it works in that way.
Amit Singh: So I save it in the advanced.
Paul: He is.
Paul: That's only I have told in class so many times. Yes, just save it here, and remove that text file to all files, save as type.
Amit Singh: Okay, okay, okay.
Paul: Okay, and now run it, that command.iva. Again, it got into TXT only.
Paul: It should not be at .txt, rename that from VS Code or from somewhere.
Amit Singh: We're tired.
Paul: commit.
Amit Singh: Only. Guys, I'm falling, I'm falling, just wait.
Paul: Okay, please follow that part. Saurabh, yes, in the meantime.
Paul: In your case, looks like it started.
saurabh verma: Yeah, it started, I moved ahead, and let me move this somewhere.
saurabh verma: Inductor, yeah. So… Now I'm at this one. Semantic question with… so I got this error.
saurabh verma: Compare all methods.
Paul: Mailverse exception, just fine.
Paul: Okay, below is telling…
saurabh verma: Is this…
Paul: Collection not found, it's telling. No, just check the collection has been created or not.
Paul: Okay, and just, be sure that, in that particular part, the name of the collection is correct. That's the only thing.
saurabh verma: So, how to check collection is created or not?
Paul: Mmm… Because.
saurabh verma: Here, here, collection loaded and ready for search. The previous step got executed.
Paul: Go above, go above.
saurabh verma: All steps are executed.
Paul: Wait, wait, go above, go above. Just check the collection name once. Otherwise, just create a new collection. That's the only way. There are no other ways around. Go at the top, top, top, top, top.
Paul: Slowly, slowly talk. Now check here.
Paul: Okay, let's…
saurabh verma: now contains this.
saurabh verma: Collection index.
Paul: 5 entities, this is fine, this is fine, because… just change the collection name, just add demo one moreu, I think, and use someplace in my… just add O, and in other places also, whenever you were doing that, just add one moreu.
saurabh verma: Broke everywhere.
Paul: The alert should find that.
saurabh verma: Okay, I'll do that. Now, one question which we can discuss tomorrow, but just a heads up. So, I am working on one project, okay, where what happens is, these are the…
saurabh verma: you know, RFP is there, which is sent by various company, companies for the tender, right? Now, in that RFP, many people who bid for that RFP, they raise the questions that, can you modify this clause or not? What is the clarification? Now, what happens is the business case is.
saurabh verma: that, against one RFP,
saurabh verma: There are approximately 20 to 30 bidders, and each bidder is giving around 10 to 30 queries.
saurabh verma: So it becomes around 300 queries. And like this, in a year, the tenders that are floated by one company, like PSU's big companies, are around 300 to 400. So they have to deploy people to go through the questions, and most of these questions are standard.
saurabh verma: So what they're looking for is developing an AI. Using AI, the standard responses can be prepared and consolidated.
saurabh verma: So, this is the, requirement.
saurabh verma: So, for this, of course, they will give the history, that is, what type of questions were asked earlier, and what were the responses given by the government, body.
saurabh verma: So, for this, I'm preparing the approach note, which I'd like to discuss with you tomorrow, and just at high level, like, when you were explaining spade and all those things, just wanted to know that, of course, RAG would be there, we'll have to put all the historical data into RAG,
saurabh verma: And then when a new RFP comes and new questions from people come, from the bidders, then the semantic search is done, and those similar queries are picked up, and the response is created by the agent.
saurabh verma: Of course, there'll be human in the loop to verify whether the response has been created or not.
saurabh verma: So, this is what, if you can spare a few minutes tomorrow, in the doubt session, then it will help me.
Paul: Okay, let me see tomorrow, otherwise I will do a one-to-one meeting.
saurabh verma: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Paul: In that way.
Paul: Alright, fine, because in this case, your data parsing is the main thing.
saurabh verma: Yes, yes, so, would need some guidance also for me.
saurabh verma: Okay.
Paul: Alright, fine.
saurabh verma: I'll stop the sharing.
Paul: Yes.
saurabh verma: Thank you, thank you for your patience.
Paul: is this?
Nitesh: Okay, Nitesh again, sorry. I just passed through all the errors now, so now I'm reaching to the errors with the millwars.
Nitesh: While comparing this, what do you call this, like, Compare all three methods, actually.
Nitesh: And here, I think the error is to collection not found, so… where do I need to change all the collections, I think?
Paul: Collection, just initially, see, even in my case, I was getting, so I recreated a collection with a demo double loop.
Paul: Okay, just be sure you are doing that in the code during the collection schema definition in that cell.
Nitesh: Very initial, right? When we started the entities or somewhere…
Paul: Once we have done the connection to the Milverse cluster.
Nitesh: Hmm?
Paul: In that particular cell, you will have that code.
Paul: Just try to re-execute all the code, one by one. In that demo, just add one O at the end.
Nitesh: Okay, okay. I'll try, thank you, thank you.
Paul: Great.
Paul: Yes, Amit.
Amit Singh: I still didn't follow Pulsar, and it is saving as text document only, it's…
Amit Singh: I deleted it, and I tried saving it again.
Paul: Because I thought about it staring, fine. I execute that fine.
Paul: I could not get, again, inside rack tutorial, why you have another folder called as Rack Tutorial.
Amit Singh: This is…
Paul: I just saw your folder structure, why inside a folder, another folder, you keep it?
Amit Singh: Oh, this one.
Paul: Yes.
Amit Singh: No, it would have got created now.
Amit Singh: roll.
Paul: Just execute the finding.
Amit Singh: This one, no?
Paul: OpenCMD.
Paul: Stop using partial.
Amit Singh: Okay.
Paul: That's so many times in class I have told…
Paul: In class, never use PowerShell. Always use CMD or WSL.
Amit Singh: Okay.
Paul: From VS Code, okay, now go to that particular project directory.
Amit Singh: Good evening.
Paul: Press Tab, press Tab, you don't need to write that entire folder name.
Amit Singh: You're.
Paul: It is there, it will come.
Paul: Hari is there, yeah, Hari.
Amit Singh: No, it's not coming.
Paul: just be sure even the correct. There's nothing that we can do. These are simple system-based steps that you need to figure it out.
Paul: Hadi?
hari: Yeah, I wanted to share my screen.
hari: Even I got stuck at, malware's download.
hari: This one represents.
Paul: Sure, sure, sure, sure. I'm adding.
Paul: If you press Skype, it is not coming, it means that it's not there, please.
Paul: It's not, like, manually, we will write, it will come. It doesn't happen in that realm.
Paul: If it's there with tab, automatically it will come.
hari: I'm sharing my screen.
Paul: Very true.
Amit Singh: It's inside many folders now.
Paul: Okay, alright.
hari: Darker in my mission.
Paul: Alright, this is fine, not an issue.
Paul: Okay, let the pool be completed. Previously, what error you were getting?
hari: Yeah, this issue I was having, but I resolved it right now, with call command and then other things. I'm not able to follow the session completely, so…
hari: Without a brand name.
Paul: Alright, alright, alright, alright, fine. Let's, while the pool is complete.
Paul: Because automatically, once the pool is complete, the image should start.
Paul: Okay, you have done that manually Docker run, rather than executing the script.
hari: Yeah.
Paul: I manually did it.
hari: I was getting error in this connection.
Paul: Because through the script, in the script, that's the thing mentioned, but other ports are also there, not only one port.
Paul: For web UI access and other things, other ports are also there.
hari: Let me convert this.
Paul: You also don't take pool.
hari: Very big.
Paul: Mmm, alright, allow, allow.
Paul: Because right now we have just downloaded the image, and then checked it is running or not.
Paul: do a rocker PS hyphenate.
Paul: Just write in the terminal, docker space ps hyphen here.
Paul: A, e-ay, I…
Paul: status, it exited. You can see now. In that way, it won't execute.
Paul: The other command Murthala shared, but it was for Mac, I think.
Paul: Execute the script.
hari: Sunday.
Paul: the script, that's… I told you, no, always execute the script.
Paul: Because manual initialization, please don't do. This is .h, do use the .bat. You are on Windows, I think.
hari: Yes.
Paul: Execute that, and, right here, like, start…
Paul: that, name of the file and start. Yes, yes, yes, it is. Check here, what happened.
hari: Unable to find the image locally.
Paul: Alright, fine, just wait, let's see.
Amit Singh: Also, I'm now inside the directory.
Paul: Then I do run the file, right?
Paul: Yes, just run the file. Name of the file, space.
Amit Singh: Name of the file… Okay, wait, wait, wait.
Amit Singh: What command should I give? This, curl?
Paul: Name of the file, then space dot.
Paul: Now that it will know.
Amit Singh: Standalone embed.pack.
Amit Singh: Great.
Amit Singh: Haven't even felt good.
Paul: There also, you can just write stand and then press tab. You don't need to copy always.
Amit Singh: Standalone-embed.bat, this is it.
Paul: Where start?
Paul: space dot…
Amit Singh: Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Amit Singh: No, of course.
Paul: Hit enter, let's see what happens.
Paul: It's not recognized as an internal or an external command.
Paul: This is how it works in Windows.
Paul: You have to give the name of the file space start.
Paul: Jake, these are all waste level.
Amit Singh: Fuck.
Amit Singh: So, can I run it in WSL? Like, that is what I was trying, actually.
Paul: And see, check the documentation in whichever way you want.
Paul: It's not my wish. However, they have told you can do it from Ubuntu anywhere. I prefer WSL if you have on it Windows.
Paul: Now, copy-paste that call command directly from there.
Paul: Go to the documentation page, go to the WSL section, go there and copy-paste those two commands. Be in the project directory, that is the bare minimum request.
Paul: From WSL to its return, go to the documentation part and please check.
Amit Singh: With the SFL only, right? Okay.
Paul: But be in the project folder.
Amit Singh: when I'm… Oh, then… I have to change the directory, no?
Paul: Correct.
Amit Singh: Okay.
Amit Singh: Forever.
Amit Singh: Available.
Amit Singh: Beautiful.
Amit Singh: Are there visible.
Paul: He cannot do it directly in this way.
Amit Singh: Same thing I need to copy.
Paul: Same thing directly doesn't work in WSL, the path is different.
Amit Singh: I was inside believers, actually.
Amit Singh: That is what it was giving error then, so I came in the home directory, that is what ChatGPT told me, and I was…
Paul: It was not running.
Amit Singh: I mean, I did all the steps.
Paul: I don't know, really, like, what steps you did.
Paul: the steps are very simple, just be in the project directory, download the script, and execute the script. Generally, that's how we do it every time, yeah.
Paul: See, otherwise, add that dot slash, generally for SH command, it is required. Because even I don't do not wish to induce the exact command.
Paul: For me, also, I know that that is how written in the documentation, so it should work, because for others also, it is working, that's why.
Amit Singh: Actually, I did not log out and log back in, that is what it said. I did this step, I didn't do this one. So, after that, I did docker ps, it was giving me blank, this thing, blank container, everything.
Paul: user mode, Docker, and other things are not required only.
Amit Singh: Okay.
Amit Singh: So this… this part is not… this step is not happening for me, actually.
Amit Singh: This is where I got stuck.
Amit Singh: Okay, let me figure it out. Let me come back in the directory, and I'll try doing it again.
Paul: Alright.
Amit Singh: Oppo.
hari: So, here, the image is downloaded right now, and I can see Docker…
Paul: Yes, container is running, no, you can see, yes.
hari: Yeah, yeah.
hari: So I can directly go and run this.
Paul: Yes, around that said.
Paul: done executed.
hari: No.
Paul: Executed it correctly.
hari: Okay.
Paul: The print logs, no?
hari: Yeah, it's.
Paul: Okay.
hari: Yeah, I see, I see here, yeah. Some reason today I could not be able to follow much, but, I'll try to,
Paul: Go through the recording in two ways. Whichever part, go through the recording.
hari: Yeah, as far as factors and all that, we're not able to correlate much. Thanks, Paul, yeah.
Paul: And do a little bit of search also, because, little bit with sparse, like, go through that, through theory, then you will understand.
hari: Sure, okay, yeah.
Paul: Alright, fine.
Paul: Alright guys, so I think we are done then for today. Let's meet tomorrow, and we will continue on.
Paul: Bye, bye everyone, thanks for joining.